hello beautiful people welcome to the
junkyard love podcast it is I Andrew
Tate's great great great grandmother I'm
happy you're here today's episode is
wonderful well he's wonderful you'll
hear very soon uh real quick just a
couple quick things
um I am playing October 30th Halloween
show in Austin I think it's Thirsty's is
the venue but as it gets closer to that
uh to that day October 30th check my
Instagram Jacob from the internet I'll
be posting info on that uh also San
Marcos every second and fourth Tuesday
open mic poetry night box combo lemonade
with the homies uh it's awesome we we
just started this Open Mic poetry night
so San Marcos Lazydays is the venue uh
like 7 P.M I think is what we're doing
yeah this is pretty cool otherwise check
out my uh my link tree and my Instagram
account if you want DJ mixes there's 50
plus of my old DJ mixes like live sets
um old stuff new stuff just various
genres uh you might enjoy it it's all
free it's on Mixcloud Jacob from the
internet if you have an event coming up
that needs a DJ hit me up I have 10 plus
years of experience I played bars clubs
casinos weddings special events holiday
parties I've played with hip-hop artists
I played with rappers I've played with
other DJs I've played tons of raves I've
thrown my own Raves uh I've played
country weddings I've I've really done
tons of tons of things over my years in
the DJ world if you need someone who
knows music even if you just need a
Spotify playlist built I do that on the
side that's a fun couple extra bucks to
make Spotify playlist custom mixes
that's a little bit more hit me up if
you need a DJ
I'm your guy I'm always looking for
freelance audio video DJ sound Creative
Design uh freelance work so hit me up
stay tuned Roadie stuff audio video
technician I have a pretty good
background at this point so hit me up if
you need me call me I will travel if you
pay the cost and some per diem don't
worry baby in your if you're in the
Austin area you can just like DM me on
Instagram and I'll I'll get back to you
or hit me up on LinkedIn or email me
junkyardlovejake gmail.com this episode
is with Will Andes if you are enjoying
hit subscribe hit like follow share
whatever any interaction really helps
we'll see you next episode knowledge is
power
[Music]
reality is
I'm doing as much as I should have been
lately but there's this place in Austin
here called Black Swan Yoga and they
offer hot yoga man it's so good it's
like hourglasses I signed up for a
membership here and there's five within
20 you know 10 to 20 minutes of my my
place so just throughout the day I can
be chilling like damn I need to get out
of the house and I can just go to a yoga
class so it's been uh that's awesome
yeah it's it's been pretty dope have you
been to any like actual classes oh yeah
yeah yeah yeah I um so my my aunt um my
dad's sister my Aunt Kim she was always
like the coolant like uh like yeah got a
degree in dance like worked in Vegas
like dance like on stage is like a
showgirl type thing
um danced in the south of France in
Monaco just like my cool aunt um she was
like you know acting in New York for a
long time and she's always into yoga and
then recently within the last couple
years she uh she opened her own Yoga
Studio in South Jersey like probably
like uh maybe like 30 40 minutes outside
of Philadelphia and
um I you know with the baby you know the
last six months I haven't did you know
many classes but but um I that's she's
the one that's kind of got me into yoga
um I remember years ago uh she told she
was like you got to come right on the
beach on the shore she's like you gotta
come to this yoga studio with me it's
insane it's like everyone loves it and
it was in an Old Barn like kind of in
the middle of nowhere like in South
Jersey like you know maybe like 20
minutes off the water just kind of in
like you know basically like you know
the blueberry Fields right like kind of
middle of nowhere and we go into this
this barn and it's the first time I've
ever done Hot Yoga I've done some
stretching exercises regular yogas and
like you know whatever but never hot
yoga and this Barn was dude I want to
say like 111 like it was hot hot like
for me as a first timer and we were
doing a 90-minute course and you know
the big thing is like you can't leave
you can't break and like mentally I just
like wasn't tough enough and I got to
the hour and I was like I don't know how
I'm gonna do the next like 30 minutes
and I like proceeded to like bounce at
like an hour and ten and I just I had to
like break the seal and I went outside
and like caught my breath and then just
like took five went back in and then I
just like laid on my back on my mat I
don't know if it was in shavasana or
like what I was but I was just you know
you know a novice just like laying there
like all right I still want to
participate I'm very sorry but you know
here I am in all my glory and like
mental anguish that's still shavasana
that's still like you know the process
of absorbing what you just took in and
just kind of uh you know laying in it at
least you went back in yeah of course of
course um I'm a you know former former
track guy you know cross-country guy so
truly a glutton for punishment when it
comes to like the physical activity of
it but like dude I I love yoga like any
like my dad hasn't gone to his sister's
yoga class that drives me insane and I
try to tell them all the time that like
it's such a grueling workout and you're
just standing in changing positions and
like from an athlete's perspective and
I'm like you know I played college
sports but like not an athlete and I
like you try to muscle it out like I
remember my first maybe four or five
sessions I'm just like trying to like be
an athlete in there and it just you know
that's not how it's done you kind of
need to like succumb to it and like own
your limitations and abilities and then
like you slowly start getting better at
least for me anyway we like yeah I got
better when I like didn't try to muscle
it out and like you know beat it in like
uh you know athletic standpoint from an
athletic standpoint yeah it is kind of
this uh this big analogy G for you know
clenching and letting go you know that
because like yoga is very much a you
know Let it Go just watch the the
struggle in your mind and allow it to
pass and just stay there and don't move
and lock into that position or whatever
it is and then there's these there's
this way of of working out like more of
a mechanical movement where you want to
be precise and you want to get exactly
right there and you want to like hold on
to it and put a bunch of pressure there
and so it is um yeah it's funny because
yoga is it gets pushed into kind of the
same thing as uh
you know we're working out like like it
is the same thing but it's very
different obviously the the Eastern
roots of it you know the mental side of
it you know the but but we're not
reading the bhagavad-gita as we're going
to oh that's a little different we get a
little right our teacher will sprinkle
some knowledge in there for us but you
know we're we're in in our own minds um
for me so it was
I kind of started doing yoga at home I
started just following people on YouTube
and doing yoga uh it just came across I
was trying to just improve my mental
health and I got really interested in
meditation and stuff and man it was just
something else I got obsessed with yoga
at first just doing it at home for hours
and hours and just stretching and being
weird and just being I mean
stoned out of my gourd and just
stretching it was just life-changing
it's pretty cool stuff
um yeah in that sense it like it does
remind me of running like just easier on
the body like less impact where it is
like you know you go for a five or ten
mile run like it's there's there's some
mental stuff you're working out
um and like yoga I think has has that
same thing but it's just it's you can
kind of do it forever right like it's
just so much easier on the body I think
it's I think it's one of those things
that like I'm always gonna like try to
incorporate you know like through
throughout the years because I think
especially my aunt like she just has a
really good way of like bringing those
like you know those ideals in the you
know Yogi World in like a digestible
like healthy way like I always feel not
only like a good workout but I feel like
the weights kind of lifted off to off of
me after I've taken her classes and do
when you find like a good teacher in
person I'm like such a people person
like yoga at home like no I never really
tried it because I know like I guess it
would never really work for me like I
need to like be that feel that energy of
like the other people the teachers the
class like whatever that like living
organism is like I love it same thing
with the gym like I just people go in
there even though everyone's doing their
own thing like there's like this
Collective community of like we're in
here you know sweating trying to get
better like I love it yeah you just said
living organism like what a beautiful
use of words I like that
because it's cool to kind of um uh get
in tune with the the vibe of the whole
atmosphere you know and a lot of times a
good teacher can be the door opener the
window opener for you you know they can
um relate all the knowledge of like I
said the bhagavad-gita and all this
Eastern traditional stuff into the
Western mind and what people in that
very room might be going through I did
um I did this yoga class A couple months
ago I had some friends come with me on a
Saturday and it was such a refreshing oh
it was right after the uh some more
income months ago right off the Will
Smith slap thing at the Oscars he
brought it up like like at the beginning
and I was like what a weird like I don't
want to learn talk about pop culture
stuff right now it's just like let's do
yoga but uh he related it to um
this beautiful thing that kind of made
me think throughout the whole class of
like how do I do the same thing he's
basically saying you know we saw the
slap that's the release of the energy
that's the anger like boom but what
happened the months before that the
weeks before that the days before that
the hours before that like that's all
building up within you and then at some
moment someone else can have control of
your energy and you walk up on stage and
just release that energy and now your
life is affected so he kind of like
explained it in this way that the whole
class I'm like man what
what a nice little you know snowflake of
information took place in my brain so I
can think about my own life and how I do
maybe those same things yeah what a
great way to like tether because
everyone watch that right like everyone
saw it everyone talked about it you know
we're all on the internet to some degree
um so like what a cool way to like
tether everyone together and like get a
message out
um using that like weird event that we
all saw that's that's really cool
actually yeah yeah we're laying it back
into something that everyone in the
class can can you know represent some
part in their life or you know we all
saw it so we can all understand the
knowledge that's that could be in it if
we look at it a little bit differently
yeah I uh that's a I think yoga does
that for me and like working out in
general as I've gotten older too like
living in the moment you know I spent a
lot of time like spending time in the
past or time in the future and like
being like this I don't know like not
ADHD but just like very East Coast you
go go go go go go type attitude and I
think like a lot of those like yoga
ideals
um and just being in it has like and not
just from yoga but from meditation and
like other things has like kind of
allowed me to like put that stuff away
and like live more in the moment on a
daily basis which I think has been been
huge for my Evolution and growth you
know over the last few years could you
expand more on like what you mean by
more East Coast mindset and then kind of
the the different things that you have
used to kind of get more in touch and
present yeah so um I guess like I've
really noticed this um my fiance uh from
from the West Coast
um and I've just noticed a lot like
everyone's different right but I've
noticed a lot of like just day-to-day
simple things where I'm very hustle
bustle
um and she's very laid back and I think
that's why hey why we're a good team
um but I think like for me
uh if it's channeled in the right way
like my mentality of like you know
for a long time as a key like I guess
you know bear with me as I try to kind
of figure out my thoughts here but
yeah yeah so like I guess I like I spent
time
not enjoying the wins right like not you
know again not living in the moment
right like and I you know my parents
kind of did this thing where it was like
honestly it's so weird but my mom always
talks about Will Smith and his mom on
some late night show and this is back in
the day like mid 90s late 90s and they
like will got a 96 on a test uh Will
Smith that is and like his mom would be
like what happened to the four points
and my parents kind of like adopted that
same mentality of like oh great you got
a 95 on a test but like you got five
points off where are the five and I'm
not saying that completely shaped me but
it is definitely in my personality of
like all right like let's learn from you
know let's learn let's learn like how
can we do better how can we achieve more
how can we get closer to our goals yada
yada yada
um and I think what it did is it
hindered me from like enjoying the wins
living in the moment like so I think
part of the east coast of like you know
it's never good enough more and more and
more whereas the West goes by you know
spending time in California whether it's
work or talking to random people at a
bar like there's you know every Town's
different there's there's hustle and
bustle fast-paced people you know in in
you know in Washington state right but
as a whole if I'm making like a gross
generality like there is a like let life
come to you mentality on the west coast
we're like oh man I'm 40 like I don't
know what I want to do yet you're you're
25 years old bro you're talking to me at
a bar like you know chill out you know
and I was never able to like chill out
and I think that's part of like why I've
been successful why I've like achieved
the things that I've wanted to achieve
and I think part of that is like the
geography I grew up in I kind of touched
on like my parents a little bit as well
um but I think there's an East Coast
mentality of like you know even just
driving on 95 like living an hour and a
half from New York City like you like
you gotta you gotta pull up or shut up
right like you gotta get out of the way
get moving or get you know onto
something else so I guess that's kind of
like my East Coast mentality or like
what I think it is or
um yeah I don't know yeah I I think I
could totally um I could totally see
that that makes a lot of sense uh just
working I mean I'm from the West Coast
I'm in Texas now but it's been less than
two years but I also have done a good
amount of traveling like my teenage
years and through my 20s so I
experienced different kinds of people
and I feel like there is a difference in
east and west coast people I mean
there's a lot of uh uh what's the word
generalities or
um you know yeah I use that word too I
wasn't sure if it was correct
um it works yeah yeah we got it we got
it yeah but but there is a it is cool
it's very cool to see you know because I
know Crystal very well I know your
fiance very well so it's very cool to
see someone she is very West Coast and
you're very East Coast but you guys do
get along I mean you just you just work
so well together like yeah dude I mean
like anyone we have we have our moments
but we there is she's like she like
knowing her are living with her you know
being in her you know orbit
um definitely has like allowed me to
enjoy the wins you know like she has
like
there's like a beauty in I don't want to
say her like Simplicity but there's like
there's she looks the world in like a
very beautiful way and it's very
nonchalant and low-key and just like
dude enjoy it like enjoy it you know
um whereas and you know I I enjoy my
life more knowing her you know she's
allowed me to be more full and whole
um so yeah it's it's been a beautiful
relationship wow that's that's beautiful
well and you guys have also just
recently had a child which I do want to
talk about fatherhood but real quick
yeah um I would like to just pin in
so you're talking about your mindset
being an East coaster like this achieve
this um you know I'm gonna arrive
somewhere someday or like I gotta I
don't want to let the people in my
family down or you know whatever it is
all the things you've mentioned plus
more
if there's someone listening that like
maybe they're stuck in that mindset and
maybe they don't see how it's causing
them harm or was there any moments where
you maybe realize like man I gotta let
more of this like relaxing thing in like
I'm I'm doing well I have achieved
that's cool pat on the back but now it's
okay to kind of enjoy what I've been
achieving was there any sort of like
that or
so I I don't think I did it in the
moment
um but like I I don't know like I like
you know like I I guess like you know
the first thing I think of is like I
wanna I wanna stay championship in high
school in the the half mile and 800
meters and I remember winning and like
my coaches or someone was going nuts on
the sidelines and I kind of just like
threw up this like nonchalant truck and
it wasn't to like
you know try to be cool which I you know
like any teenage boy like tried to like
be like I'm the man I don't care about
it wasn't that it was like I couldn't I
couldn't get the happiness you know I
was worried about like the party I was
going to later that weekend or like the
argument I'd gone in with my parents the
Night Before the Race and like I just
like wasn't you know there's like it's
so funny like the the things that you
you know for me at least like it's like
it's movies and TV and podcasts and
talking to people and events in your
life but like I think of like the Kung
Fu Panda and I think of like the Sensei
he says like something to the effect of
like if you you know have a foot in the
future and a foot in the past you're
like pissing on the present right and I
that for whatever like I've heard it
before you've heard it different things
but for whatever reason like the Kung Fu
Panda one like landed for me and I love
cartoons
um so yeah I think like that when I
think about like my life like that's one
where I look back and go wow that's like
weird and then even like graduating
college which doesn't seem like this
amazing thing but I'm the first person
for my family you know with my last name
to to you know graduate college like a
four-year University like it's something
to be proud of and it never like felt
like that like it was just like all
right cool like get a job you know and
then it was a cool you got a job like
you know okay you're off you're off Mom
and Dad's like cell phone plan you know
and it was just like these like I don't
know and then it was like okay like you
know you get you you know move out with
your friends like get a place in Philly
and you know party and enjoy yourself
you know go out with girls you know go
to Eagles games and then you know it's
just kind of like no I don't want to say
going through the motions but like just
not being able to like live in the
moment um so like to back to your
original question of like
to you know to someone that's doing that
or living like that like you're you know
the again like I don't want to talk in
complete cliches but like we're kind of
in that Avenue
um like the the destination is the
journey right like all the stuff you're
gonna like look back on and enjoy like
sometimes it's like the the mean
potatoes of it right it's like how the
sausage gets made it's like that's stuff
along the way that minuscule
insignificant stuff like that's the good
stuff you know
um so I think if you can kind of take
that approach that like you know
um I'm gonna like be present and like be
here um and I think again you got to
figure out for like yourself what what
it takes to to be present right and
sometimes it's as simple as like oh what
you know what's causing me anxiety like
oh it's the big test I have like well
then study like don't procrastinate
because you're not gonna be able to be
here because you're you know your brain
is what you haven't done yet or you know
you lied to someone right like well that
you you know and again I think these are
all like mistakes that I've made in my
life like procrastinating on something
or lying to someone and like you know
lying yeah like helps me manipulate a
situation or achieve some sort of you
know some something I'm trying to do but
like in this I it would ruin me for you
know weeks depending on the severity of
the situation so I think like living
kind of like honest and true to yourself
you know knowing who you are and like
you know what those will like to do and
like owning that you know I think that's
probably the one of the most difficult
things but if I'm like giving someone
advice it's like you know know thyself
right like learn what you like learn
what makes you tick what you like to do
and then you know own that and enjoy it
um and I think that that will allow
someone to to be a little less hustle
bustle and success success success
because ultimately you're driving
towards something that you know might
not bring you you know everything you
think it will you know and if you can
stop and smell the roses a little bit
and you know enjoy the the hard work and
the journey I think that's like where
where true happiness and wholeness kind
of Lies yeah man I think you hit it
beautifully I think it did actually yeah
it really is like this uh you said it
well when you when you describe it being
a journey you know it's not a
destination it's not somewhere that you
arrive it's there there is you know
actually as as I was framing the
question that I that I had you answer
um I would I would like to point out
it's not like I'm trying to say be less
East Coast minded be more West Coast you
know no because no I think part of my
six yeah yeah I think part of My Success
is in that like it's never good enough
like right you know what I mean like
part like there's that internal drive to
like and that's still there right but if
I can like balance that with like oh man
I kicked ass today or wow that was a
great workout or you know what I mean
and not necessarily in the past tense
but like you know like like just
enjoying that that hard work or that
tough thing
um it kind of allows you to enjoy the
whole thing better and then that
internal drive it's not like it's a
negative thing it's you know part of my
greatness in the sense yeah yeah no I
mean hard work is is a great thing
there's a lot of things that I have
accomplished personally and a lot of
things that I have um been able to
experience in my life because I worked
hard for it you know it's the the
ability to to be present and enjoy what
you have often does come on the back of
hard work you know the the you know it
kind of reminds me a little bit the you
know the East Coast mentality we're kind
of talking about here reminds me a
little bit about stoicism of you know
kind of uh you know pick up pick up your
heavy Rock and get walking you know what
I mean like um there is there's a lot of
Acceptance in the east coast mindset
that I think is important
um not so so a lot of and again I'm
generalizing but a lot of the West Coast
is kind of
um how can I make this better this is
the this is all I have now so I can make
this better more more comfortable more
safe more blah blah blah and then East
Coast is kind of um deal with how it is
you know it's cold outside get to work
in a lot of ways yeah and there's a
there's love in both of those and I
think as I've gotten older as I've
um you know just met more people I kind
of I kind of get the balance of both of
both of those things you know we're
calling it East Coast West Coast but you
can call it all these to you know
masculine energy feminine energy this or
that you know it is kind of a balance of
um I don't think any one of us or any uh
Coast has it all figured out I think
it's just certainly not you know finding
that balance of achievement but enjoying
what you've worked for you know being
being here but also having a little
foresight of what you could be like be a
better version of yourself but love
yourself
yeah yeah and I think you made a really
I think important distinction or point
that I was you know grasping for which
is like that west coast of like you know
you're almost able to like see things
for what they are versus like this is
how they are and I think sometimes that
West Coast like you know kind of bigger
picture laid backness it allows people
or you know situations to like they can
you can kind of see how to fix them or
see how to like make them better versus
like the East Coast like just deal with
it you know what I mean it's freezing
outside like you know trudge trudge
along to work um and I think that's
that's an important thing that like
Crystal just for example like I guess
we're just using East Coast West Coast
because it's like my It's My Life
um and we're talking
um but yeah like she's kind of able to
like see things from you know that that
view that like I can't because I'm like
in it you know and she can kind of like
from afar look at things and be like oh
let me let me make this suggestion or
let me like you know talk this talk this
out in this way they're like I can't see
because it's like go go go so
well I mean it's it's a it's big of you
to you know as you get older to kind of
uh see where she can help you you know
there's a lot of like strong masculine
traits that sometimes you gotta bend the
need to I'm like okay I think I think
maybe she does know best there's
something for me to learn here and
there's plenty for for her to learn from
you I'm sure you know that's yeah I mean
we're a good team
um you know when we're like in any
relationship but when we're really
communicating and there's no
there's nothing holding us back and
we're like just freely boom boom boom
like we're we're good you know what I
mean whether we're playing a board game
or whether we're like you know trying to
figure out how to like you know
um organize this thing or schedule this
thing like when we're you know I make
suggestions she gives me feedback like
when we're not communicating well
um is when we like you know we get into
a little bit of trouble but we're we're
good and you know talking out our
thoughts and feelings we can kind of do
whatever we we want to do in a sense
yeah the the two people together when
they when they combine they create a
third superhuman of sorts
um yeah now you've actually created a
superhuman child so uh dude how's being
a dad how do you like it it's good it's
good I have found um I found patience
that I didn't know I had you know
um
and I think it's uh
I think it's you know every parent's
like it's the greatest thing I've ever
done like that whole that whole thing
and there's there's a lot of Truth in
that
um the funny thing for me I guess is
like Crystal carries the baby right the
woman carries the baby
um and then they the baby's there and
they kind of already have this
connection
um you know and I I don't have that
advantage of like you know growing the
baby I'm just like they're supporting um
and there's so many challenges and
things that come your way that like
everyone in the world can try to talk to
you but like you kind of just have to do
it like I feel if we ever had another
kid like I feel
so much more prepared I know so much and
like I kind of can't like I'm gonna
guess the first of like my really close
friends to to have a kid and you know
people they always say like you you know
people want other people to have kids
because it's like oh you know join the
club have a kid like their kids like I
don't I just want to like be there for
my friends because like I feel like I
know a lot and I have a lot to offer so
like I want like one of my friends to
have a kid just so I can be like dude I
got what call me at 3am I got you like
I'll come over I'll show you whatever
you need
um but back to like
for me and it you know my my daughter
um Bennett like and maybe it's the same
with the sun too I I don't know but like
our relationship grows like every day
right
um it kind of feels like a like a
romantic relationship in that sense
where it's like we're like building this
thing um because we didn't we didn't
know each other before you know and
neither did Crystal she's inside her
belly but there's something there's
something there and for me like I like
any you know any father first time
father like freaking out like you know
in in all the ways
um but I feel like we're like you know
we have a bad day or a bad few hours and
you know I you know she's crying or
upset and she's not laughing at me like
we're no and then the next day isn't a
great day right or we have two bad days
in a row and then she doesn't sleep the
entire night like it's it's it's
cultivating this like you know we're
building this this relationship together
it reminds me a lot of like a romantic
relationship
um it's very interesting now yeah yeah
love is definitely you know we think
yeah love is again another thing you
don't arrive at it's something that's
cultivated you know it's something just
learned about every day and it's
something that's um
um it's fragile too you know because
some some days like when it's
frustrating I'm sure if you have a
couple bad days in a row and like other
things maybe work isn't going right
maybe there's an argument like it's like
man I can't even access that love that I
was just drowning in yesterday you know
yeah yeah we're in like patience right
it's like sometimes like a couple
different times
you know I'm the oldest of of four kids
and my my sister's seven years younger
my brother's eight years younger than my
youngest brother is 13 years younger so
I have experience with like changing
diapers and babysitting but like not
like a true infant um or a true baby
that's you know there's this is your
baby this is your reality this is your
life you know um so you yeah like you
know you're working your butt off you
get home from work and you know there's
no there's no relief
um of like oh I have some me time like
it's your family time which you
eventually kind of morph that into your
own me time right
um but there's there's been moments
where you're like okay like I need to
put the baby down and I need to like run
to the bathroom and like take 30 seconds
to 60 seconds and like collect collect
my patience because I feel them you know
Getting Thinner and thinner
um or like the babies around and like
having a discussion with Crystal and
it's like she's not you know being
receptive or she's not you know I'm I'm
being a jerk whatever the situation is
and then like you know voices are
elevated and it's like yo like that's
not that's not the environment we're
trying to you know what I mean and it's
just like you kind of have to like it's
a humbling you know check yourself
experience uh where you're like who you
know who is the man that I am and
growing into and you know who do I who
do I want my daughter you know to see
and feel because like you realize very
quickly that that they they will they
will take as like you know as much as
you you know you kind of vibe off of
them they are Reviving off of you from
from pretty early on you know um I felt
like this sense of like
maybe not intuition but just like this
little like sponge like a couple weeks
in where it was like oh like you know
and then like you're you know like
simply as like rocking them to sleep
like I felt like so my my thing with
with Benny is like I would like have her
in my arms and then I would close my
eyes and I kind of knew what she wanted
but then I would like whatever felt like
very like you know um like lethargic and
sleepy to me like that would like and
then I started thinking about like my
fingertips and my hands as like these
like you know a way to like give my love
to her which like again it's like crazy
um but just like these different like
mental tricks you kind of do and then
when I'm doing that or I'm like all
right like I really need to go to sleep
but like I'm stressed like I'm I'm like
when you're in that zone like that it
just for me it like never led to like
her actually going to bed in a timely
manner like what what worked was like
all right like my fingers and hands are
like vessels of like love and support
and sleep and dreams and like yeah I
don't know like that's like that was
like helped me like forget the
frustration or forget the tough hour we
just had and it was just like I'm here
for you you need to go to bed I love you
you you need some sleep you're well fed
your diapers changed we left we loved we
cried like we did it all we'll do it all
tomorrow you know what yeah what a
beautiful way to create like a present
story for your child you know like if
there is some sort of magical way in
which um they're sharing in in your you
know thoughts or like whatever you're
kind of seeing as you close your eyes
and you're saying your own fingertips
become this like warm embracing like
flowing wave of sorts you know uh yeah
it is well so so that is uh that is one
of the beautiful things about love in
general you know certainly when it comes
to a child but even you know at times
when
um you know just a romantic relationship
when you love someone or even just a
relationship I suppose is your
peripheral edges expand you know who who
we are in the edges of of our body you
know we think we're you know some
something inside this this meat sack
inside this body and our edges are you
know our our the edge of our legs and
our arms and our feet and our hands and
our head and whatever
um but just as if as when we are driving
in a vehicle we kind of expand that now
we know where the front bumper is we
know where the back bumper is we know
the headlights are we know if we get
close to anything with those you know
now multiple feet of of distance around
us
um it's going to cause damage so you
protect those things you don't want to
hit anything with those and you do kind
of the same thing
um when you let when you let someone you
love into your peripheral of of who you
think yourself to be you kind of combine
with them you kind of um you're now uh
uh you know intertwined with that being
in the edges of who you think yourself
to be are now expanded into that other
person so
um yeah I'm rambling about uh just kind
of the way no absorb as well one yeah
and it's you you are like I like the car
example a lot because like you ride
around in the car as a family right so
like your car Your Vessel is not exactly
yours anymore right like I kept saying
like yeah like my life not in a negative
way but like my life's no longer mine
like I live my life I still have me and
I still want to do things but like
there's a greater good that like Crystal
and I are both working on and like you
know it's for Benny now right so like
the car example I kind of love because
like when we're a family unit in the car
like there feels like a like a
specialness on a vehicle to love yeah
yeah yeah it's not just getting to the
store you know to the party or like to
my parents house or whatever it's like
it's we're we're out in the world um it
is weird how like having a kid kind of
like
expands your like your love you know in
general you know like and I think for me
personally it's you know and again maybe
it's back to that East Coast thing but
like I found patients I didn't have like
I'm loving you know the neighbor's dog a
little bit more like I'm able to like
look at a stranger in like a different
way like this stranger was like a
helpless little baby at one point you
know what I mean
um so like to kind of thinking about
things like that
um and you know it's it's raising kids
you know it's it's not it's not the
hardest thing in the world but it's like
you know it can be tough and yeah you
know people screw up
um so like kind of like having having
like a just bigger softer side for like
humanity and community and like I'm so
much more
mentally thinking about like my
community because now I have a daughter
and I don't know exactly what that is
it's probably pretty simple but
um yeah I'm like thinking about
like you know the other people more and
you know what are we doing you know that
kind of collective
um which is kind of we touched on that
with like yoga and the gym and like that
Collective Consciousness
um which I knew existed but I you know
was kind of doing me and now doing me
involves like protecting and loving and
like serving this this this beautiful
little baby
um so like thinking more about like what
what I can do for you know my fellow man
um you know to to help my daughter in
the future or whatever that is I don't
know I haven't totally figured that out
no yeah no that is that is a good
perspective because we are kind of
contributing you know the collective
unconscious is is made up of us you know
we are a piece of it we're a certain
little percentage of that pie and it
also is a little bit of that planting
planting seeds of trees not for you to
sit in the shade but for your
grandchildren to sit in the shade of you
know that I don't know if you've heard
that um yeah for sure before but it is
sort of you're you're I'm sure there's a
natural you know you can pretend that
you don't notice it but if you if you
have just the ability to kind of think
ahead a little bit you can visualize oh
if there's no nice friendly world
uh that's being created in the future
then what is my daughter gonna live in
you know so you kind of want to see the
community and the you know even just the
civilization that you're raising your
daughter to be a part of you want to do
good for that too so I could see how
that's a kind of a reoccurring good
cycle of caring about one another
yeah and it feels like I and I don't
think this is the case as a whole but
like I feel more of a sense of community
with her birth but it and I think people
think the way that I do in that like
sense of you know goodness
um it just in the world with today like
I think there's
there's there's far less people like
controlling this Narrative of like we're
all split and everything's screwed up
and like I think there's more of so many
more people that are you know thinking
the way that we think or that like you
know I think there's a lot more goodness
than like social media and television
media and like I think there's so much
more goodness and sweetness in the world
than like hate
um so like even though it feels like the
narrative is like you know more split
and hateful I don't know if it's me just
having a baby and like being you know
more full of love but I I do believe
that there's so much more goodness than
hate
um today
yeah I think so too man I mean uh me you
and Crystal when you guys were in Austin
a while back we had a wonderful
discussion on this like kind of this the
the state of the world and kind of How
It's painted and we talked about the
media and stuff and yeah yeah you're
right I think uh a lot of the podcasts
and YouTube stuff that I listen to let's
you know some of the books I read kind
of
kind of helped me understand a lot of
this you know a lot of our more
nihilistic negative thinking or like
kind of thinking wow the world looks
like it's on fire or something lately
it's it's kind of the the people who
control the lens we're looking through
the people who can are in control of um
not only lens but the picture frame or
the the frame of of the lens that's
that's being held in the lens they're
they're pointing at these things that
want to keep us online they want us to
watch them they want us to talk about
them they want they rise quickly to the
top of our discussions and they rise
quickly to the top of the things that we
debate about and we argue about in this
like war-like way of speaking
um because it's it's seemingly the most
important it's the same thing when
you're driving and you see a wreck it's
like what you can't look away you just
you want to see what's going on it's
it's a a threat that may be happening
it's tapping into our evolutionary
biology and kind of gaming us but the
truth is there's a lot of beauty as well
um you know even though these are the
things that social media and the news
and our you know media in general is
kind of putting a ends on for us to see
it's not the only truth there's a lot of
beauty and there's I think living in our
Modern Age is kind of an act of um of of
remembering that and not being too
caught up with this damn thing you know
not looking for this window but looking
through this window here like of life
you know what's right in front of you
heard about this game the other day
where
um you go to dinner with your friends or
whomever your family and the first one
to touch their phone has to pay pay the
tax um yeah and I I haven't played it
yet but it's something that I'd like to
propose at some point you know so long
as people aren't working and it's not
like going to affect everyone I'd like
to I'd like to kind of you know throw
that on people as we sit down and order
the appetizers like see if people are
down for it
um because I think like you just said
there's so much value and like you know
tuning out right yeah yeah yeah no
that's exactly focusing on what's right
here and it's it's distracting I mean
your whole conversation with your
friends at dinner could be about one
Facebook post that like while we're
waiting for them to bring water we're
all kind of looking at our phones and
it's like man Hillary Clinton just did
this that's some [__] and he talked
about for 45 minutes right as opposed to
like just let it organically kind of
develop and I guess you know that is
part of our Organics now like we're tied
to these things
um but I I I I don't know I I wanna I
wanna play that game and see see what
happens you know see how uncomfortable
people are like and I'd like to like do
more of that
I'm on my phone a good amount for work
um but I and and you know at night time
here and there but you know raising a
daughter like it's also had me like you
know kind of change like who I want to
be you know what I mean like I don't
want you know it's impossible she's
gonna like realize what a phone is and
she's already like if we're on them or
doing something like she reaches for it
and grabs it but
um having a child's been like really
good for me because it's like forced me
to like look at myself
um in like a whole new light
um but especially the phone thing
because it's it's you know and as like
you know raising a young girl like it's
it's it's it's scary out there I mean I
love the internet like I always make the
joke but like the internet is is
undefeated you know like I see something
on the Internet and I have crystals
saying it now like she's like the
internet's on the feed man she'll show
me some hysterical video
um but there's a good time and place for
it like which we've lost like that that
Cadence for the cell phone because it's
in your pocket it's next to your bed
it's you know it is all day every day
um and I think that there's got to be or
I'd like to kind of
um dive in personally into like what
what my Cadence will be with my phone
um and same thing with my with my
daughter you know I want her in the
outside world like you know mixing it up
with the people and not not stuck to
this digital version of of uh you know
what what life is you know through that
lens you know
yeah I mean yeah it's man I I wonder
about that a lot like um
just one day if I have children
um
I mean right now it seems so it seems so
easy like like no no phones I'm not
giving them phones till they're 16 or
something you know but what an
impossible task and now you know I'm
sure plenty of people said that same
thing and I mean it's it's gamed it's
completely made for our psychology to
love man it's bright yeah colors it's
it's amazing in every way
um so yeah it's definitely probably
something I can imagine it would
probably take up a good amount of your
thought I mean I think I wouldn't mind
just thinking how am I gonna you know
make sure my child is is aware of this
they know how to use it very well
because they're going to be living in a
world where it's important to know your
way around technology for sure
um but also you know it's it's a tool
that you use and how do you make sure it
doesn't use you that's something that I
think some you know people our age and
and a little bit younger are are
definitely dealing with you know we had
social media in in our phones and stuff
when we were in teens or late teens so
we're kind of able to look at life
without it and life with it and see how
much it affects us and and who we are
with it and without it and hopefully
teach other people and like you know
like I remember being an adult you know
before Instagram right so like all those
like rewards and I'm not I'm just using
Instagram to like give us a time frame
here but like they've they've only
recently in the last I don't know
however many years
fine-tuned that addictiveness and that
reward system right so like when when we
first had smartphones like
they didn't know how to completely
Captivate Us maybe from like an
ergonomic standpoint and a user and like
you know obviously they were taking data
to figure out how to make them better
and smarter and faster and you know more
more user-friendly uh but like we're in
this age of like
how do we keep the masses eyeballs glued
to this thing at all times you know
um which like that that
sort of like money
um and effort into that like that's
where it's really kind of started to
like scare me and I like my plan like as
a as a gross plan for the future like I
you know I want my daughter to be 13
years old realistically before she has a
cell phone now maybe I cave at 11 or 12
because she's playing sports she's in
middle school you know she needs to be
able to reach out to us but you know
obviously you know there's restrictions
or you know uh I need to know who you're
texting you can't just text and call
anybody like these numbers need to be on
approved list like oh I made a new
friend okay great what's their phone
number who are their parents like I
don't want to be a helicopter painter
like yeah you have to let your kid like
you know scrape their knees and stuff
but I will be diligent when it comes to
technology
um just just because I I think it's it's
the future it's unavoidable um like you
said you know anyone growing up today
needs to know how to how to operate in
this world
um
but it's definitely a scary one I mean
we're you know we're seeing you know
massive depression and you know there's
just a lot of negative side effects
because like you know we're not it
doesn't seem like we're supposed to live
in these you know giant PODS of cities
where like be as connected as we are to
people across the world it's it's it's
it's a wild time man yeah no it's
something very new in the human
civilization of the human species it's
something completely obtuse compared to
what we've ever experienced before I
mean think about the 2007 was when the
iPhone came out and and the world is
completely changed in every direction
and way and uh we're we as consumers are
like hardly able to understand it and
the people who are at the you know Helms
of the ship you know a lot of times we
think like oh everyone who's at the core
of these is they're evil and they're all
like I don't think they understand it
they're just following their quota
they're just letting capitalism just
completely take them away with next next
upgrade more get more eyes on it more
product activity from us means more eyes
on our devices yes that's good we don't
we don't stop and think about the whole
thing right like how many of those
high-ranking officials or Executives
like actually understand the algorithm
right like you know what I mean it's
maybe a handful of people like most of
them are like Plug and Play like this is
this is what the Netflix algorithm says
so you know your show's on the home page
your show's not you know what I mean
it's like we're we're kind of becoming
slaves to like this AI algorithm cool
and it's it's a new area of um you know
human
I don't know but propaganda I guess is
is a way because it's
that they're now in control of things
that they almost didn't want to be in
control of they are affecting humans in
the way that we the way that our culture
runs in ways that they didn't plan on
it's like well that's just kind of like
a whoops didn't mean to see that like
right you know they discover I'm sure
you've heard arguments about um you know
this AI doesn't favor uh people of
African-American descent because blah
blah it's like because this complicated
thing just doesn't see the darkness in
their skin pigment versus it's this
complicated Pandora's Box is a great
word for it is is we're experiencing we
did all these things and we're like next
next but there's a lot of little doors
that are being opened that we have to
deal with that are affecting our
Consciousness our Collective
Consciousness and us as individuals and
how we um you know form in groups and
how we react together in tribalistic
ways again it's gaming our biology
there's just a lot of things that are
that we're dealing with as a species
that nobody really made a plan for and
so it is up to us with Elegance to try
to
you know enjoy it but not be too caught
up in it you know not really indulge
yeah and I I think that's like the happy
medium right like there's that there's
that sweet spot of like all right I'm
gonna use this as a tool I'm gonna laugh
at it but I'm going to be able to like
put it away
um and be a normal human because like I
don't biologically we're not like we're
not built for this you know yeah we're
not we haven't evolved to be here like
things are moving really really quickly
um did that kind of remind me of did you
hear about that AI rapper
That's crazy dude okay so so I also uh
oh yeah we'll go ahead and explain this
AI rabbit for some reason okay so
correct me I I I don't know too much but
my understanding is an AI rapper was
created got signed to a record label in
some you know some like some like I use
record label I don't know if that's you
know musically like still what's
happening but got signed got a deal and
then I guess the the creation of the
Avatar of this rapper is black you know
again I I don't know too much but like I
guess started using like you know the
n-word you know racial stuff and then
proceeded to get canceled yeah and to me
it's like I I you know I don't mean to
laugh anyone's upset or offended but
it's it's just hilarious
like AI rapper Avatar creation record
deal
cancel like yeah like how we like this
is a rabbit hole that like yeah I guess
object is funny you know it held up this
big mirror that we didn't want to look
at it it got weird really fast so so
basically what you do when when uh when
will said they created an AI uh rapper
basically what they do is they have an
AI they have an algorithm that you train
you show it you know a hundred or a
thousand or a hundred thousand different
songs and you say make me a song or
whatever it is so they have this
database of different things that it's
pulling from I haven't looked into it
enough to know like how they pull
information for its quote-unquote
personality like how it gets to the
point where it has an avatar it creates
that doesn't identify with those things
and that's why it's saying saying the
n-word
um but I will say something very
interesting I'm I'm very front row seat
for this whole AI rapper thing yeah yeah
I figured because rap is
man rap and hip-hop as a culture is is
interesting to put to try to to to to to
calculate with computers and numbers
because
you know think about like kind of the
dis and the respect and the the um
there's different sides of hip-hop that
are very deeply intertwined with culture
that I don't know that you can in ones
and zeros explain very well because
there is like right now I could in a
very respectful
two hip-hop way write a diss song
against Kendrick Lamar like I'm a nobody
so it's going to go unnoticed but if I
was you know say Mac Miller or we've
heard these dis songs before between
these rappers it's very very personal
but also very on the surface and it uses
this language of hip-hop that goes
through the culture that everybody
listens to and respects it I don't know
it gets very complicated um Danny Brown
the rapper if you've heard of him he
actually has he I haven't listened to it
yet but he just came out to this song
against this AI
and so that's genius like what like is
the AI going to come back at him is he
going to clap back is it going to get is
it gonna get weird like
yeah I I I hope so just just to see the
theater of it um I I love Danny Brown by
the way the um have you heard his new
podcast so yeah I'm not like not like
every episode but I've heard bits and
pieces
um I love Tom Segura too so like you
know I listen to like a lot of his stuff
but that's kind of how I heard about the
Danny Brown podcast but
um dude I've been on Danny Brown for
years like that weird show he had on
viceland like he's a the way his brain
works is is super duperative interesting
I love it yeah and his like his
experience is is a wild one like some of
the stories he has like he's a he's a
wild man yeah I really like that he has
not only his own show but I mean I liked
him he was on Joey Diaz's podcast and
he's been on um your mom's house with
Tom Sakura and Christina P he's been on
there a couple times too and he's just
someone man whatever he's saying you're
listening to because his way of sharing
his stories is just so honest he's yeah
like he's he as he's explaining this
[__] he's realizing that he was he was
completely a terrible person in this
story yes but yes he's like I don't know
man [__] it like he just he just comes
to terms with it and moves on you know
his perspective is awesome
he also I think has one of my favorite
laughs like of all time dude like he's
he's good he's he's good yeah man I was
so like that's like I'm a huge podcast
dude you know I mean I'm in my car for
work I'm driving around I'm visiting
people so uh and I'll do the radio thing
I'll do Sports I'll do music or like
serious or whatever but like I'm I'm a
junkie for the comedians
um podcast just because like
I don't know
um there's you know the free form
conversation for hours where you can
really get to know someone like that you
can kind of become a fan of them and you
know um like really like learning how
people think and feel I think uh I think
podcasts have at least for me in the
last like 10 years like become a big
part of like my um consumption of uh
entertainment um for sure yeah man I've
I'm in the same boat I've become such a
huge podcaster just in the sense of I
listen to podcasts all day like I listen
to yeah I'm always just listening to
podcasts it's it's I don't know what
what other people listen to they just
listen to the radio and stuff what yeah
I mean I guess like music like Spotify
you know which I do I'm like what do you
think
music
2006 of you um dude I'm just trying to
drive home from work yeah
it's it's the anniversary of Mac
Miller's death I'm trying to honor him
too by listening to some albums right
like what the [__] I think that was
yesterday dude so I
um I think it was yes I'm not 100 on
that um I just saw a post
um and that was like enough for me so
dude I didn't realize I kind of had an I
love Mac Miller
um so I moved I moved to Florida in I
moved to Fort Lauderdale uh from
Philadelphia in like 2015 I think and
took a job it was great for my career
kind of like I needed to do it I also
like personally just called through bad
breakup and it was just like I needed to
to get a hold of myself so I moved on to
Fort Lauderdale and dude the divine
feminine came out and I fell in love
with that album and I I had always been
a fan of Mac a little bit but it was
like me being an idiot from South Jersey
Philadelphia I was like oh Pittsburgh
you know like [__] the Penguins right
like just like stupid sports stuff but I
like I knew kids was good and I knew
that he was pretty good and then my
little brother was like yo this dude is
the real deal
um so I bought my brother like tickets
to see him
um in Atlantic City uh at like the House
of Blues like for his birthday or
Christmas or something uh and I didn't
even remember this my brother reminded
me of it but anyway so I fell in love
with the divine feminine and then it was
like dude Massachusetts
no no he took he took a friend but I've
seen Mac I've seen Mac a handful of
times and um but yeah yeah uh dude you
know what's funny like I I got so drunk
at one show it was at Festival beer in
Philadelphia like I I saw him but I
didn't see him like I don't have any
memories of it because I was a young 20
year old kid
blasted yeah yeah and it's just like I
know I saw him I swear to God I saw him
but like you know it's like you know
what what song is it physically there
that's all I remember yeah I was just
like we connected however I don't even
share a single thread of the memory
um but anyway I fell in love with with
that album and I was like wow this guy's
doing like a lot musically
um that I like am in awe of
um and then you know swimming comes out
and I'm like absolutely floored but so
he passes
you know all the celebrity deaths that
like have happened and dude I've been
saying for years that like so many
people are famous now because like 50
years ago there was three movie stars
and now there's so many famous people
that like we're gonna have dead famous
people every day in 20 30 years it's
gonna get crazy in that in that way but
him and Robin Williams are the ones that
like really messed me up because I was
just such a true fan of those those two
um and in very different ways but like I
love everything a lot of the things that
Robin Williams did as well but so that
floored me when he passed and then
circles came out and I had like this
like he didn't do it you know like this
isn't right you know there's something
wrong about this and then I caught uh
you know maybe like almost maybe a year
went by um and I didn't like I I had
heard bits and pieces but I didn't like
listen to it straight through like I
would other Mac Miller albums and then I
heard a piece that I really liked was
like whoa this is sick and then I kind
of looked into it and I read like in a
vulture article about I forget his name
but the guy that finished it for him and
kind of like his you know how look how
he put the pieces together Max family
yeah I I forgot the guy's name um but
this guy's like one of those like
musical Geniuses
um man I wish I could remember his name
I can look it up if you want me to or
whatever
yeah but it was a it was like a
uh well we should get this guy's name
just so we can just so we can put it out
there um throw it in later yeah but um
so anyway he like Matt comes up to him
at a party and he goes he says and I
guess like it's all in this vulture
article which is an amazing read
um
the something to the effect of like Max
said like oh man I didn't even know if
you would like if you would consider
what I do music
and then have you you'll like this so
then the guy this guy is a genius like
we have to figure out his name but I and
I will in a second but he he says to Mac
like do you know what the Webster
definition of music is
and Mac was like nah and this guy's and
again I'm butchering this and I
apologize but he says it's like it's
like it's like four words if the Webster
the definition of music is like a
collection of sounds I'm pretty sure
it's something to that effect right like
a collection of sounds is what the
definition of music is he's like dude so
like when you think about the Simplicity
of that there's like endless
possibilities and Beauty in that
definition so like what you do bro is
it's more than music so that's how that
was their first meeting
um I'll pull this guy's name up but um
anyway so I like just had this aversion
to circles and I read this article and I
was like all right and then I just I
just listened to that album start to
finish and was floored
um and he talks about them
yeah it's dude it's really good
um and he talks about like these are the
songs because he talks about how they
work together and Matt just did I guess
he didn't have the he didn't have the um
like the the know-how of like hey I want
this to be more Bassy I want this to be
more echoey like whatever you know and
I'm I don't have a musical bone I just
know what I like but he like he didn't
know how to like do it you know
um and this guy did so Mac would like
say I want this to sound more like this
and the guy would like oh so like do
this and this and he kind of taught Mac
how to produce and edit and whatever
that world is
um so he explains he goes through the
album and says like I didn't touch these
six songs these four I just did what I
thought Mac would want you know he's
like so I I [__] around with these
four not like a lot but he said he tried
to do as little as possible so when I
read this article about like this guy's
love for Mac Miller his his his
dedication to him um and how his family
kind of reached out and asked him to
finish
um
and I guess my understanding is it was
like swimming in circles and then there
was supposed to be one more album after
um yeah which is really heartbreaking
but it's just funny how you know you you
I'm not married to any idea that I have
like I've kind of you know old enough
and smart enough to know that I'm not
you know I'm not married to any like
ideas like I'm I'm I'm willing to change
and think and evolve um but I like had
this like this love for this guy and
then this like as just a pure fan and
then this like aversion to like someone
finishing his work because it's not his
and I thought I was taking this like
altruistic stand for like my fandom for
mac and like him
and then like I read this article and
I'm like Lord and then anyway so last
night I like played I saw a post that it
was like the anniversary and I was like
uh circles boom start to finish I was
like cooking dinner and baby was asleep
and just like rocked Out the album and
it was awesome oh oh it brings you
somewhere too so yeah I didn't realize
it was uh that close to the the date of
death uh anniversary I'm gonna have to
listen to some mac later today too uh
yeah I'm I'm no I know it was September
um I I'm not sure exactly shocked me
it's probably been many years by now
it's because I still remember that was
definitely it's so interesting that you
say mac and Robin Williams Because those
are definitely two of my top that when
they died it affected my day my week my
um well because we have this thing you
know back to what you said about how
many you know famous people there are
you know basically how many people
outside of your immediately family
family friends co-workers acquaintances
that you know and you know kind of love
in a weird way there's a little bit of a
warship but an appreciation you know
when it comes to famous people that
you're a fan of yeah
um and now we have the internet where
we're connected to these people in more
ways than we ever have it's not that we
just see Taylor Swift's album once every
two years we get to see her make it we
get to see her break down about it we
get to see her talk about it for hours
on a documentary afterwards we get to
see her tweet every day about how she's
frustrated with it or she had a bad hair
day and now we relate to her more like
we're more connected with these you know
famous people or artists than we ever
were and so when it's a loss it really
is a loss I mean that's like yeah it's
something different than it was
and it's like there's it's kind of funny
the way that there's like there's no
like mysteriousness to like Stars
anymore
um all right so real quick the the guy
his name's John Breon b-r-i-o-n
um yeah if you just like vulture Mac
Miller circles John Brion it's a it's a
decent article yeah yeah it's just kind
of like
like the confidence that it was done in
the right way to like listen to it but
um there's no like there's no
mysteriousness when it comes to like
your celebrities or your Stars anymore
just because we're like we're living
with these people 24 7. you follow them
on Instagram you see what they have for
breakfast like I I I like I don't want
to be like the old guy that's like oh I
missed the days when like it's really
cool to be able to like like the access
to these people and to know what's going
on like it's really cool but there is
something
lost in the mysteriousness I think
um
who's the uh
like the the amazing actor that played
Bill the Butcher in Gangs of New York
um Daniel Daniel Day-Lewis okay Dan de
Louis like that dude I'm guessing
doesn't have an Instagram right and he's
probably like you know that dude he like
he's like a shoe cobbler in like Italy
in the off season and I I don't know
exactly but seriously there's no there's
not many
guys like that anymore because they're
like you you're never gonna get your
music out there if you don't have an
Instagram right you're never going to be
able to like you know you're just never
gonna make it like you have to like give
so much of yourself
um and I you know I not that I feel bad
because I think it's like you're you're
doing it for money and all the things
that you want and you know success and
you you know you want to get your music
out there or your movies out there
you're you're acting uh but it's I I'm
not sure it's worth it you know in a lot
of like anonymity is is for me like
Priceless
um you know like uh yeah like rich and
Anonymous versus rich and you know
famous like all day every day for real
you dude I think about that a lot um and
I've had people on that have changed my
perspective of even how I do it because
I'm a very
um I post a lot on social media all the
time
um I've always been someone who like
keeps up to date I share my opinion I
like living out loud as um you know I'm
an artist a Creator a poet so like
here's my opinion maybe it's different
than yours
um and you know I think about I've had a
guest who talks about how he would hate
to be that exposed all the time like
like trying not only to explain yourself
but then also trying to control what
people think about you so they don't get
the wrong idea and okay I did share that
moment when I was feeling that way but
that doesn't represent who I am and
you're kind of like shaping your avatar
to other people and making sure your
your masks are um you know uh in in a
way that is presentable that doesn't get
you you know kicked out of the the
hierarchy hierarchical group hard words
to say out of the hierarchy you know
because uh yeah for sure exposing
yourselves gives you more opportunities
to
um be ostracized for being different
um for people to misunderstand or
misinterpret who the thing you're
putting out or who you think who they
think you think you are
um and it gets very yeah exposed is is a
word that I had a podcast guest use and
sometimes I think about that a lot I'm
like man do I really want to be
um uh out here being so vulnerable like
why don't I just shut up and kind of
share only the certain little aspects
that are gonna reach fulfillment in this
way or I'll you know I'll arrive somehow
some way you know whatever yeah I mean I
again I know you a little bit
um so but like I would think that if
someone watches you for uh a small
amount of time I think they would think
that you're coming from a pretty pretty
good place of like love and acceptance
you know like that's when I think of you
I think of you know honesty love
acceptance you know whether it's your
rapping or your you know some some posts
that you've you know taken the time to
write like I I don't know I don't think
and you know I don't know you behind
closed doors in that sense but like I
don't think that you need to be worried
about being exposed because I think
you're you know you're pretty true you
know yeah yeah yeah well thank you I
appreciate you for for saying that too
um and I think it does rain true I think
a lot of my uh a lot of the magic these
days the last few years especially is my
like I'm genuinely trying to live
honestly like I'm trying to live openly
in in with truth and um kind of just
stumble through life out loud in a lot
of ways with this kind of stuff like the
podcast is you know it's everything I
want it to be and it's it's about the
guess but it's also very
um and so it's a lens to me too you know
you're getting whatever I'm going
through and it's kind of my blog in a
lot of ways so
um yeah but is it something I struggle
with I think I go through phases of
wanting to close down and um you know
because because sometimes other people's
outside energy can can throw off what
you're doing I think there is some sort
of you know if there's if there is
somebody that's out there watching me
not wishing the best for me like I think
maybe their intentions might have some
sort of effect in some ways if I'm not
if I'm not careful or maybe I can be um
influenced in certain ways that
um I didn't really want to be or or
something I don't know yeah no I think I
think that could be exhausting you know
um but I you know I don't think that
maybe it's an impossible ask but like
maybe like not letting not letting that
you know those voodoo doll thoughts you
know for somebody you know somebody that
doesn't have good feelings towards you
or thoughts or wishes like that you know
that can't don't you know it's easier
said done but I think that you can you
know not rise above but you can you know
like take you know that's fine that's
fine let it let it happen because you
know like that's yeah exactly exactly
um
you know yeah you can't get 95 good
comments you get one that says like you
suck and you're like man I suck it's
just yeah right well and that's the
thing is like yeah reading 95 good
comments is amazing but like it just
takes one shitty comment to like to like
you know mess you up so then like you
know I think the solution there is just
like no comments like again like you
know you're growing you're trying to
interact with fans you're like wanting
to see like you're wanting to see
constructive criticism
um but you have to like I guess you I
guess you have to like look at it
through a lens of like you know not
taking it personally and just like
looking at it from but again you don't
know these people or you don't know
where they're coming from
um I guess you probably if I'm you like
maybe you're like getting asking more
people that you whose opinion you
respect and love to watch and comment
you know like you send me you send
something to me and your will you'll
watch this when you can you know
um and tell me what you think you know
and at least you know like my you know
I'm in sort of impartial and you know my
my critiques or my suggestions you know
come with wrapped in love you know
wrapped in like you know wanting you
know the best for you right um and you
know we know each other enough we didn't
grow up together so like you can kind
you know you can kind of be in my head
as I write this critique or these
suggestions or tell you what I like or
don't like and at least maybe that way
it's not like this nameless faceless
comment it's like a comment wrapped in
you know friendship
yeah yeah I I feel like that's a good um
note to any sort of artist or anybody
creating anything or sharing anything is
um not all not all opinions are
not that not all opinions aren't valid
like you know anybody's opinion has
validity but
there's there's only certain people he
should allow the validity in to to your
actual art like it's if it's someone you
love and care about or somebody you ask
personally or someone
um that you generally respect their
opinion but if it's someone you don't
even know it's some random like Reddit
Troll and they have like a Ferrari as
their DP like you know yeah Ford guy 58
69 you know like you don't have to take
in his what he says the same way that
like your loving best friend just told
you you know so there's a difference and
it is it is an act of kind of glancing
that stuff off I think that um the more
time passes the more I am admittedly
pretty unfazed by a lot of
good comments and bad you know I try to
yeah I struggle with sometimes I'm like
okay listen to what they're saying like
let the love in you like they're giving
you appreciative
um you know uh uh Praise of some sorts
cool appreciate that cool feel that and
then you know let that go and in the
same sense I do that with any sort of
you know negativity or anything that
somebody's um if they're disliking what
I'm doing I okay let's take it in for a
second and then I'm gonna let it go
because you don't want to like you don't
want to punish the ego but you also
don't want to stroke the ego too much
you know yeah I always appreciate the
people that like give me that that like
that that you know that thing I don't
want to hear you know you have a couple
people hopefully in your corner that
like tell you you know tell you the
things that you don't want to hear you
but you need to hear right um and then
you like you kind of at least I start to
like bucket people whether it's like
colleagues at work like I like one
bucket I have which I think a lot of
people like positive people are like
they'll never give you any criticism
it's just like great job great job I
bucket them in like the mom column where
like no matter what you do your mom's
like great job funny you nailed it
um and I think people just default to
like and I appreciate that positivity
but like I'm not I'm not getting better
if you tell me I do great every time
right so it's how can I you know so then
when I do find someone that like you
know kind of gets up my ass or tells me
what's going on like Crystal for
instance like part of the reason that we
fell in love and we get along so I was
like she doesn't she doesn't sugarcoat
[__] like she she gives it to me um but
actually my my boss at work right now is
like one of those people where like I am
in awe of her ability to like get [__]
done and the family that she's raising
and she's just a badass lady
um but on top of that like she she kind
of like she doesn't hold back and I
think she knows I can take it and she
has high expectations for me so
um you know uh and I you know yeah I
have a couple people but I think those
are those are important people to
identify and then and bucket them and
then like hold them close because
they'll they'll make you better yeah
right being able to to allow that in you
know I think there's a lot of uh
fragility that I had to grow out of out
of like not even allowing anybody to
criticize me or critique what I'm doing
like no I know best or there's even a
side of me um that on my artistic side
where I'm like you just don't understand
what I'm trying to portray here I'm too
much yeah you're too much of a genius
for yours some [__] yeah but um you
know allowing those opinions in and
looking at like dude someone else else
with a different perspective offering
you
um you know their lens or their view on
something that you're doing that you
could possibly be then better at
afterwards than allow that in that's a
gift man that's that's a good thing
criticism for sure and um critique and
you know just just someone who who is
close enough to you to offer that that's
something that not a lot of people have
or they have boundaries up against so no
nobody's ever people are too afraid to
say things to them in a lot of ways and
that's not the spot you want to be in
yeah I I get um
sometimes I like will cross a line too
quickly too soon with someone but like
and it's not like this this
um it's not something I've kind of
thought about it's just kind of the way
I operate where if I like if I say
something inappropriate or I get a
little silly or I bring up a you know
taboo subject like I'm kind of like
skipping the small the small talk to get
like to get to like some good juicy
stuff right and it's like putting effort
something yeah you you've kind of
experienced that where like I'll you
know I'll I'll hop skip you know and
jump like too many spaces and I'll have
to backtrack and be like Oh my hey I
hope you hope I didn't make you feel any
anyway but like I I think people that
know me are getting to know me they
realize that it's like you know I just
don't want to do like the small talk I
want to get to know you I want to know
how you feel about you know important
stuff
um and also it gets like a good
conversation that can like keep my
interest going
um right but you know I don't know I I
think too I think often these days where
we are living a little bit with our foot
in our mouth you know and I think and I
don't like that and I think
I think we should we should say what we
want to say and be unafraid and not yeah
I think I think it's a bit dangerous in
a place of um such beautiful freedom and
Free Speech you know and then um I know
you say the word Free Speech now it
suddenly becomes this like conservative
thing Suddenly It's like in this weird
area of conversation I don't mean it to
be that but um the uh I think there's
something about speaking freely being
yourself asking what really comes up
like if something kind of maybe personal
comes up about this person you're
talking about and you just say it just
say it and if they're if it upset them
then you say oh well look I'm sorry I
totally didn't mean that you deal with
that repercussions but I think I mean in
my experience when you're just open with
people and you say what's really on your
mind you talk about these things that
are said to be taboo you suddenly are
able to connect and you're more open
with this person on a level that the
Small Talk would have never reached to
in in a two weeks of working side by
side that person you know it breaks
through the [__] and you actually
get to be yourself and they get to show
who they really are as well and I think
that's that's good man yeah
um and I I'd like you know like you said
I I definitely put my foot in my mouth
I've I've made the mistake too of like
if we're discussing something or I'm
like trying to get a conversation going
like I've in the past come across as
like too opinionated but I said to you
earlier that like I'm not married to any
of my ideas but for like a long time
like I came across as like married to my
idea but what I was really trying to do
is like this is what I think and feel
like what do you thinking like without
being like what do you think and feel
but like doing that like this is it this
is the truth as I see it like I want
someone like I want 20 minutes later to
be like I'm wrong you're right you know
like wow like I didn't think of it like
that but I'm like just trying to get the
conversation going or just trying to
like get a rise out of you to like see
where you're at and how you stand and
I've like definitely gotten better of
like not coming across like as you know
maybe East Coast opinionated or like
whatever it is but like not so dead set
and being more like just finding a
better way to like organize the words so
I'm not so so set or coming across so
set in my ways coming across as like
well what do you think about this rather
than like this is how it is
um so I'm even like fine-tuning that
like you know how I how I talk to people
and you know interact with them
um and I think that's kind of
a
um a byproduct of like where we are with
like people putting their foot in their
mouth where I've had I've like you know
I don't want to upset people or rock the
boat or have people like leave the house
party and be like well will Andes is a
real piece of work you know what I mean
I want them to be like that dude is wild
like people I you know I never thought
we'd be talking about that thing or you
know I didn't know that you know I
wanted to be like more happy and less
like offensive I mean again I think
that's like part of like being with a
woman from the West Coast like her kind
of framing things for me that like yo
like you're coming across
super duper opinionated and like I don't
think that that's your intention but I
only it's because I know you like
sometimes people don't know you and then
you need to like you need to be like
that but you need to do it in a more
digestible way
right right yeah I know that makes a lot
of sense do you I feel like you're
generally a growth mindset person like
you're someone who you're reciprocating
to you know so of course Crystal you're
gonna like listen to what she has to say
but is someone just saying hey you kind
of came across this way and you not
being like well now [__] them they don't
understand me you you saying I did okay
that's interesting like I didn't mean to
and kind of relearning where do you get
your growth mindset from have you always
been like that um I I don't know I think
like I spent a lot of time when I was
younger being trying to be like on the
toughest coolest you know I just spend
too much time not being authentic and
not being like true to myself and like
Goofy and loose and more like you know
I'm cool and I really not that I regret
anything from my younger days it's all
growth but like I think when I look back
in my life I like I'm I'm just sad for
that little kid that he couldn't like be
more of himself because he was so
insecure that he wanted to like front
all the time he thought being the
toughest you know smart mouth kid was
better than being sweet and nice and
like I just you know I feel I feel for
that kid you know what I mean and
nothing like happened to me and you know
what I mean like I but it was just it
was I didn't learn that lesson at like
15 16 17 like unfortunately like I
learned that lesson in like probably my
early 20s
um and I think for me that that's kind
of where it comes from that I was like
late to the party in my maturity
um with that sort of stuff uh so yeah I
guess that maybe that's why I'm so
growth oriented still is because it took
me a long time to get to where I was
then and even where I am now you know
it's like
get busy living or get busy dying you
know what I mean so I'm gonna I'm Gonna
Keep keep on growing yeah no that's a
beautiful thing to where you can see the
contrast of how you thought before and
how you thought now you know I think I
find myself kind of in the same category
of you know there was plenty I learned
you know I I was consistently learning
and I was very growth mindset in a lot
of ways but there was a lot of
um a lot of aspects of me and my
personality that like I thought were
super [__] awesome and didn't need to
change even one bit and then as you get
older you're like oh oh it hurts because
I was doing that you know oh that's why
it hurts you know you start to realize
that your actions affect like your uh
your cognitive behavior you know your
actions affect what you think about
years later or you know whatever it may
be you know so you you kind of because
I've always had that growth mindset but
um
yeah there's I think there's part of it
that's Amplified you know in kind of
becoming quote unquote a man I guess
there's there is this jump from Peter
Pan Boyhood to like damn man I gotta
like I I need to be [__] responsible
once in a while I gotta you know I'm a
person in this Society I contribute to
this Collective unconscious I'm
responsible for my own future my my
loved ones you know I have a certain
percentage of responsibility for my
loved ones and all these things and it's
uh it's kind of this thing once you once
you take a look at and once you once you
face it and accept it you can't look
away so you're kind of right you kind of
forced onto that path of now it's time
to like grow up and be a big boy but
it's it's
um there you can have it any other way
you know you can't live as a boy until
you're 75 years old you're going to have
a life of victim mentality
yeah I am I had a I had like a therapist
I got I got kicked off the track team my
freshman year in college for fighting
another Runner um anyway and they made
me go see like a therapist at school and
the I was like nothing's wrong with me
you know what I mean just that total
like invincibility
um and he was like do you know what the
word humility means and I honestly think
I was like yeah of course and like I'm
like I kind of know what it means but I
don't know what it means and I should
have just been honest but like you know
again it was I was fronting
um so
you know and then I look up the word
humility and then you know I don't think
that landed then but like that's one of
those things that has like it's traveled
with me
um just because you know this guy was
taught me a good lesson um
that I didn't learn until years later
but you know maybe like because I was 18
at that time so it probably took me a
couple years but that you know his his
asking me what the word humility meant
like and you know that that landed some
years later so I I appreciate that
therapist for uh for kind of giving me
that lesson dude it's very interesting
moments that happen especially in you
know teenage years or early 20s or
whatever that you now realize our
significant
um you know Divergence of your path
there there's significant pieces of who
you are today but like at the moment or
even a couple months after like you
didn't you kind of brushed it off but it
was actually kind of in your it was
working like without you knowing it was
in your in the back you're working on
itself and working on you and changing
you and then later on you're like damn
that was actually kind of a profound
thing he made me look at humility and I
didn't know [__] about it until I looked
it up for whatever you know
yeah and it's like I love that that it's
just like sitting there like you know
like waiting right just waiting and
waiting or like churning and working and
growing like and more things are like
you know letting this thing grow in your
your brain until that bubble bursts you
get all of it yeah water is getting in
once in a while a little bit of more
water and then a little bit of sunlight
leaks in and it kind of grows and you're
not aware of it yet but it's still it's
festering and it's growing it's dude I
remember uh when I was in high school I
had a I had a couple moments like this
but
um I had just it was before I think some
sort of dance after a football game or
something
um I didn't play sports or anything I
was just a skateboarder mainly would be
a good way to describe my role in um
high school but uh we had just you know
smoked a fat blonde out by the by the
field uh came into the dance and we
completely reaped and I was completely
stoned out of my mind and um I remember
the assistant principle pulled me to the
side and he's just giving me this this
whole thing about how I'm a leader and
whether I realize it or not people look
up to me and blah blah like there's no
way he didn't know that like I smelled
like I put a nug up his nose there's no
way he wasn't unless he had never smoked
weed there's no way
um but it stuck with me in that same way
afterwards I was like I just got away
I'm just I'm so high bro and he didn't
even know that's what it was right
afterwards and dap up your hobbies and
go have fun and probably got drunk later
whatever but uh it worked on me and it I
feel like over time it it kind of I was
like man I can't ignore that I can't
ignore the fact that there's there's
situations where I become the alpha male
and people are mimicking me and they're
looking up to me for answers and
suddenly if I if I notice it uh suddenly
oh yeah I realize that I am the one kind
of leading the group and they aren't
doing what I am suggesting you know
um and that's a weird place to like talk
about you know to talk oh I am the alpha
and people listen to me but there is
moments if you become aware even in high
school that you are a leader of some
certain sort of people and whether you
go in and out of it or not people follow
you and they they follow your your lead
and who you are and who you act there's
people who are watching and I think it's
something that probably you know as a
father as parents as you guys get older
it's something you're going to be
ultimately it's like the way that you
are putting dishes away in the cupboard
like you're going to be aware okay
there's a there's now a three
four-year-old watching the way I do this
and the way I talk to this person on
speakerphone there's someone listening
to me and they're learning how to talk
to someone on the speakerphone and you
know there's all these things that
dude they're then they're little sponges
like they they will imitate you they
it's so yeah dude like the way you put
away dishes like something as simple as
that like all of a sudden changes just
because you don't want to make a noise
or you don't you know what I mean you
don't want to scare them or any little
thing that you do you know what I mean
like I'm gonna teach her how to use a
fork and a knife so like I need to like
not have my four you know what I mean
like I want to do it the right way like
you know have matters it's it's a it's a
wild experience you made me just think
of something though like I I've kind of
always felt like a leader in certain
areas but like as I've gotten older I've
noticed that like I'm not needed as a
leader in this group of friends or in
this situation like I'm I'm a I'm a good
as an assistant here I'm good as a
supporter like I like this um which is
like uh I for me like again like in my
mid-20s maybe a tough pill for me to
swallow like whereas like I'm trying to
like you know run the situation and it
was like this moment calls for you to
like
sit back and like be commentary or like
you know chill out or like you're
running security right now keep an eye
on everyone you know what I mean like I
think like
you know maybe not identifying as like
leader or follower like there's so many
other jobs within a group I think that's
a good way like healthy way to like
think of it but I also think it's like
healthy to like identify like what that
moment or that group of friends or that
time calls for
um because it might be your moment to be
a leader you know if you're excellent in
you know whatever
um and you're in a situation and you
know your your expertise comes in and we
need you like that is your time to step
up and do it but like just in general
like life like sometimes sometimes
you're just like an assistant sometimes
you're just a body and it's like that's
that's kind of an interesting
interesting way to to think about things
but I I think it's I don't ever want to
like totally like generalize or
categorize something but like I do like
putting things like in buckets for me
you know what I mean just like a healthy
way for me to think about things
um and I don't like go and hang out with
this group of friends and like all right
I'm the I'm running like security like
I'm like you know Mac from always sunny
and I'm like like I'm you know like that
you know what I mean
um but I do I do think it's like it's
interesting to like not not need to be
that leader and not not need to be that
Alpha all the time yeah it puts um yeah
it's there's situations that don't
always need someone to stand out and be
the leader like it's going to flow just
beautifully without anybody really
trying to rise above any ranks even
unconsciously
um and it also it also takes a little
bit of stress off off your shoulders
like a lot of the times I would part of
my something I used to say all the time
which is so silly to me now but um I
used to say I'm a control person I like
to be in control I like to know I like
to and um when you're overly a control
person
you know sometimes your friend groups
it's like you're overly planning things
like I'm always the one starting the
group message and I'm always the one
that's planning this and I'm searching
the airbnbs that we're going to go to
and there is times for that and that's
all great but there is a lot of times
where we put a lot of do pressure on
ourselves where our friends are like
dude you don't have to do anything like
we're fine we're going to show up just
tell us the time or like cool how would
I pick the restaurant this time like you
don't have to pick it every time
whatever it is you know there's this um
this this ability to not have to control
everything and just it's gonna be fine
let's just do what we're gonna do fall
into what we're going to fall into and
it's just gonna be all right man it puts
a lot it takes a lot of the stress off
your shoulders 100 I have like family
members that like they love hosting but
they're a terrible host because they are
stressed out and it's like you you can
feel it like this untangible like Aura
and like whatever like you walk in the
house like damn they've been arguing
because 2 000 square feet
you guys have been arguing all day why
are you feeling this like why'd you host
like anyone else could have posted
um but it is funny and it's like I don't
know again it's like you know like a
wise person kind of learns from other
people's mistakes
um because I love hosting and I've even
found myself like not putting it on my
guess but like internalizing like I
gotta get beer I gotta get ice you know
what I mean like we gotta get or do we
have enough food like should we cook
more you know what I mean like that
whole thing of like yada yada Rat Race
um and then like just you know realizing
like all right like whatever we don't
have we can get everyone's coming it's
more about like everyone's coming over
like let's watch the game let's chill
out like they're gonna meet Benny like
you know like whatever that dude like
that objective is like that's the thing
man like the rest of the stuff like you
know chill out man I can feel your West
Coast just coming through yeah dude yes
it is that you know if we're so obsessed
with how is it going to go we got to
make sure it does this and at this time
we're gonna do this and the game's on it
this time and there's not enough Bulls
in that in that they're not enough to
take in that bowl and you just get
stressed out you miss like what are you
doing dude you're hanging out with your
friends right
missing the whole thing you know oh my
God yeah stop trying
good good yeah I was gonna say like I
saw something about on you know saw
something and it was like how old are
your parents it was some conversational
podcast it was like I forget who it was
but I was like how old are your parents
how many times a year do you see them
all right we'll be you know they're if
they're gonna live till they're 80. and
you see them twice a year and they're
50. that's 30 more right like whatever
the math is yeah and like doing that
like that
um uh you know I don't wanna I'm trying
to like search for a good word
um like not the evil math but that like
that like that that gut-wrenching math I
think I think is helpful
um because you know I've even noticed
that like you know having a daughter and
like you know like I remember like
saying to Crystal like you know maybe
three or four months before she's born
like I'm you know I'm like kind of being
like you know like insecure I wasn't
being serious I was like joking but I
was like are my are my friends still
going to want to be friends with me you
know like as we like lay in bed like I'm
joking she's like yeah shut up dude but
like what it was is like I
yeah but like I know I know that like
there's certain realities that are like
existing right like my my friends don't
have kids yet and like we live in the
city right now and it's amazing and I
know my one of my best friends is 10
blocks away my other friend is like 15
blocks away like so we're close like we
see each other but like I don't have the
same Freedom that I had before like I
got I'm more on a schedule and I got I
got you know bigger fish to fry so I'm
not going to see them as much but you
start doing that like hardcore math you
know and then like all right like I want
to get I want to get her to like a nice
School District in the suburbs when
she's ready for kindergarten so like if
you start thinking things like that like
as long as you don't let it like ruin
you like it can it can you know help you
calculate the importance you know again
like living in the moment right like it
can it can allow me to be like I get I'm
gonna see my friends
150 more times the four of us hanging
like you know my crew whatever 100 times
before I move out of the city well like
you know that's then then those hundred
times like get a little bit more special
um and I don't need to do anything
differently than what I've been doing
for my 20 you know 30-year friendships
with some of these dudes
um but like yeah you just it's uh
there's like Beauty in that like
gut-wrenching hardcore math no there
definitely is they're definitely it's a
it reminds you to be a little more
present because you're like well I'm
here and and now I'm accepting that it's
not forever like I don't get to do this
forever I can't just call up for the
rest of my life this is not even
available to me these these friendships
that I have or the ability to even live
this close to them and so it's it's not
so much about like how do I squeeze more
juice from the fruit it's you know enjoy
each bite like when you are with your
friends put your phone away you know
when you are with your friends try to be
at peace with your mind so you can
really just listen to those you know
laugh with them and be with them and hug
them and just be you you know be present
that's exactly what it is but I have
this line I wrote a couple days ago
hug your friends they ain't free
when you're with your mom be present
because she's doing her best and her
best might be you and it's it's
essentially just like
it's something that I've learned from my
own experience you know I went through
many years of like my mom was the the
evil doer and she's the reason why I
like my my childhood and teenage years
were so tough and she's she just held
all of it for me and once I was finally
able to forgive her now our relationship
is this friendship that I'm so present
when I'm with her like I'm so like like
we just joke and we play and I allow her
to be completely her and she allows me
to be completely me and there's no like
you're the mom that you never showed up
and I'm this hurt child and you need to
play that game of even though I'm 30 and
you're this old like you have to you
know it's it's all this healing of now
all there's left is to just be present
when I am with my mom like I don't know
how many more times it's gonna gonna be
with her maybe that's a numbered thing
that I can calculate but when I am yeah
and I I don't think you necessarily need
to calculate a calculator but it's good
to yeah
right right yeah yeah did you guys ever
talk about
stuff
oh yeah
um okay yeah we had some pretty heavy
conversations
um yeah good good there was a lot of uh
I'm a pretty open book about that stuff
too um there's
you know Shaylee my ex that I was with
for 10 years she helped me with a lot of
that there was a lot of that like with
as much as I tried to like hide that and
keep Shaylee from that because it's like
I'm not trying to have this girl see
that my whole family is a disaster and
like right you know I'm not trying to
have her see me scream at my mom or
anything on the phone so she helped a
lot with that there was a lot of healing
there
um and then yeah my mom
you know a few years back I kind of went
through
I I realized in every way possible like
the things that happened in my past are
making me do things in in causing me to
think in certain ways that is causing me
more harm so I need to get to The Rook I
was very like root cause of my ales like
things that are hurting me and things
about my personality that are shitty
like they're from these things at the
root so let's get the root cause and I
went through you know multiple years of
just digging up as deep as I could any
childhood trauma that I had just [__]
pulling it out by its roots and so I
went through like I was it was a crazy
nut case for sure um for at least a few
months you know it was just a lot to
dishevel but my mom through circumstance
my mom actually ended up moving in with
me and me and Shaylee and through that
time we were able to like have plenty
you know I'm down in the basement going
through these like weird hypnosis and
like childhood you know past regression
and all these weird [__] and
um I go upstairs and talk to my mom
about what I just went through or I
would have some sort of thought that
came through my childhood and I'd ask my
mom like hey uh did this actually happen
and she was like well from what I
remember here's what happened or she
actually had a bunch of letters that my
father had written to her while he was
like
um just super drugged out but I was with
him
I if I remember correctly I had
basically read these letters because he
would write these like I love you so
much and I'm so sorry I'm doing like
these just super vulnerable letters and
I was just a young buck he would I think
hand me these letters to hand to my mom
so I would of course read them and so I
was very much like help Dad Mom you're
evil like you don't help like look at
he's hurting
so anyway I was able to like read these
letters again talk to my mom about them
you know this was just a few years ago I
was like 27 26 or something so
um but yeah it's a I was able to like
revisit all of this stuff from a place
of in my home I'm in a safe place
um everything else is okay I can re-dig
it back up and like really look at it
all right now like what's what's true
what actually happened and what can I do
now versus this story that is harming me
and harming people I come across you
know because when you have unhealed
stuff it um it leaks out in ways that
you're sometimes unconscious of
um or you you turn you find ways to turn
your eye away from
so yeah man I I uh I definitely dug up a
lot of the childhood trauma now me and
my mother are at a place of of a good
spot and I'm good with my dad too like
we're we're friends too
yeah it's it's good to like
a lot of people don't get that
opportunity right like it's good to like
have those heavy conversations or like
to like do that self-work because like
you do do you like you feel like lighter
you know what I mean and again like I
remember I went to your we stopped by
your house
um and you're fine um but like then like
seeing you in Austin like you would you
just seemed like just lighter dude like
area you know like you weren't being
weighed down so whatever you're doing is
working man
cool yeah yeah lots of yoga no yeah
right yeah lots of yoga no I I think um
I think you guys probably saw me have
the tail end but that's what I was doing
a lot at that that Castle Rock House man
that was uh yeah not just that there was
a lot of creation there's a lot of
artistry happening there I was creating
a lot and writing a lot um but I was I
was just I was getting everything that
was harming me psychologically just
pulling out its root and like it took me
I feel like it took me you know Eckhart
Tolle he had um he had like a spiritual
awakening you know like his perception
of who he is and is his uh uh you know
connection to Consciousness as a whole
it's just completely the way he
perceives the world is different and he
had multiple years where he pretty much
just I guess just sat on a park bench
and just [__] sat there and just like
tried to ground himself in reality and I
feel like I had kind of my own version
of that in many ways because I dug so
hard and I um I I like face all this
[__] and I had like these crazy
experiences like through hypnosis and
yoga meditation and breath work and a
lot of cannabis and I just yeah I was
like on this Retreat you know and it it
did it admittedly took me I feel like I
hung out a lot of people during and I
talked to a lot of friends during and
then sometimes I want to kind of go back
and like dude I wish that I could
explain to you that I know that I'm
always been a little bit weird but when
you hung out with me I'm not always like
that I was like yeah I had just
experienced this or whatever you know so
I'm I'm still pretty weird but I'm a
little bit more normal these days I
think well dude and I think you know
people people realize that it's like you
know people you know your Ebbs and flows
like you're gonna be some version of
yourself you know you're not always
going to be perfect you know um some
people are more consistent than others
right but some people like you know I
know that I had a period of time with
like my friends where I was like just
heavy like things in the past and
mistakes that I made were weighing so
heavy on me and I couldn't like live in
the president and enjoy myself because I
was pissed off myself for this mistake I
made like I couldn't you know couldn't
work it all out and it was like
affecting like how I interacted with the
world you know
um
but that's like you know that's when you
know you have good friends that like you
know rock out with you no matter what
and like you know sometimes maybe you
have to have a conversation and um and
then sometimes like I think as I've
gotten older I realize like am I having
that conversation for myself like does
my friend need that conversation and
like I've kind of realized like
sometimes like I would feel like okay
the right thing to do is like clear the
air and in most cases it probably is
like communication's healthy but like as
you get to like know people and stuff
like sometimes like you're apologizing
for yourself like you're not apologizing
like for the right reasons or you're not
you're not having this conversation to
clear the air for the other person or
for the right reasons like you're doing
it to almost like absolve yourself of
like this guilt or this mistake or like
oh man I was so weird that time like
whatever
um and then like I don't know you just
kind of like you know sometimes like you
have friends that like you know it's
water under the bridge and it doesn't
even need to be said you know and that's
like there's there's that's cool you
know when you have a when you have a
friendship like that I mean either way
even if you bring it up and it's like
you know you look just not you know
sometimes not
not letting it affect you so greatly
that it's like should I should I like
just do what feels right here you know
your friend you know has your back he
befriends them for five years 10 years
20 years whatever like you know yeah
there's uh you can come up with this
huge apology and I pretty honestly sorry
about and then they're responsibility
like bro I literally I I haven't thought
about it a single time so yeah dude I
don't know I love you anyway when yeah
what are you talking about you're like
you know that time we got in the fist
fight you know I was a totally like dude
I don't
that explains like most uh you know male
on male corals when it comes to friends
it's a lot of like I've had literally
straight up fist fights where we fought
two times when I was friends with
friends and the next day we're like bro
I'm sorry that was some [__] you know we
hugged each other we're best friends
again you know dude and that [__] makes
you stronger right like it's like like
any great relationship like you've gotta
you Wade the Waters of like some top
times and some like hairy situations and
you're like you're better because of it
um I do my my best friend and I have
gone in multiple fist fights and I'll
never forget I'm pretty sure the last
one we got in maybe second class only
ever got it
I I was sitting on the stoop at the
house and he was getting back to the
house after like uh you know four or
five mile run and I didn't expect him to
be back we got in like a pretty like a
decent fist fight scuffle the night
before another roommate broke it off and
he comes around the corner and we look
each other and we just both have this
[__] eating grins on our faces and like
you know like literally like Words
didn't even need to be spoken
um I actually just gave the uh I gave
the best man speech at his wedding
um in May of this year
and it was uh it was awesome that was a
nerve-wracking experience because I'm
pretty good on my feet I'm pretty I'm a
Salesman you know like a killer yeah but
dude it was really it was really tough
um was that your first time getting a
best man Suite ever yeah first time ever
um and I don't and that's the other
thing too is like my brothers I have two
brothers
um Michael's 13 years younger than me
Zach's like eight years younger than me
and they're definitely like super duper
close you know they're only like four or
five years apart
um and I'm so much older so like I have
I'm tired with them now but like me and
my brother Mike like we didn't start
getting tighter until he was like 17 18
and I'm like 30 at that point so we've
kind of lived these different lives and
now I think we're really close but like
I don't know if I'll ever speak at my
brother's thing because it's like you
know they're they're kind of each
other's best man I feel like yeah so my
boy Vinnie is like my my rock he's my
dude so and it was funny because like
the weeks leading up for months leading
up I knew kind of the framework I was
there I want to talk about this I want
to talk about this I want talk about
this
um I want to like work through it like
this so it's kind of like formulating in
my head and that's kind of like my
process it's like up here until it's
like on paper and
I knew because it was like friends from
high school friends from college like
like I've been friends with any since
we're like 10 11 years old so like our
lives are wrapped up in one another's
and I kept telling myself like dude you
know everyone like it's no big deal you
know everyone and then like a week or
two out it was like yo you know
everybody like it went from like the
fact that I knew everyone went from like
this calming factor to the fact that I
knew everyone was like nerve-wracking as
[__] you know like it was just right it
totally flipped
um uh but no I mean I I think I gave a
solid like B plus a minus speech
um you know Vinnie told me it was like
the best speech of the summer of all the
weddings he went to and stuff like that
so that that that felt good
um I had one moment where I like I just
like forgot my transition and it was
like kind of like an emotional part and
I'm a pretty emotional dude and I froze
for a long time when you're like like
probably like five to ten seconds I was
like I had a [__] you know what I mean
just like you know scared yeah like
searching and everyone thought I was
getting choked up but what it did is it
I would have cried like a baby at this
part like during this transition and the
it saved me from choking from getting
choked up and then the only other like
and again this is just me being like
super critical of myself
um I just like I just kind of like
rushed the end a little bit because I
kind of like after that I was like yeah
I missed like one sentence I wanted to
say something about his fiance to kind
of like wrap up like that part in like a
nice little bow but like and honestly it
went great I just I'm super critical of
myself but uh yeah it was I was
definitely it was the bed I think it was
the best speech of of that night and uh
yeah yeah it was good it was it was good
but a nerve-wracking experience because
you only get one shot you know what I
mean like if this is there's no there's
no redos right yeah and as much as it's
it's natural and it's chill and it's
like it's your best friend and you know
everybody it's also like you know
everybody and it's your best friend and
you want to make sure you do it right
and you only give one opportunity and
you know there's vomit on your sweater
already mom's spaghetti for sure for
sure go ahead go ahead no I was gonna
say like my friends like me I I think we
hold each other to pretty high standards
so like had I gone out there with a
piece of paper like I would have never
been able to live it down you know like
that's just like the weddings we've been
to like our other friends that were
there like it just would have been like
you can't you can't have a piece of
paper like the notes out there are you
yeah exactly exactly like I just that's
just the way my friends are so it was
like all right that's not and I I
wouldn't want to do that anyway I can
memorize a you know it was a it was a 90
seconds to two minutes so you like my
boy wanted it like short and sweet to
the point
um but yeah it was a it was an amazing
experience but I
I quite literally
I was struggling to live in the moment
that morning you know like we're getting
pictures done and I'm like enjoying
myself but I'm like doing that thing you
know
um and I I as soon as it was over I was
like I was I I was thought I was gonna
be able to be like cool but even like
all of a sudden like a thing of Doubt
would creep in like an hour later like
it kind of like it kind of [__] me up
a little bit uh which I'm glad I did it
and I like wanted to do it it meant so
much that he asked me like you know it
was a great honor um but it's just funny
the months passed that it's like I'm I'm
I'm okay with it
um but it was like I put this insane
amount of pressure on myself
um that like kind of like you know
didn't allow me to like you know enjoy
My Best Friend's Wedding to like the
highest degree because I had to speak a
little bit so that's a part of it though
that's yeah no it is it is and I'll like
I'll I had a great time like all my
friends you know um but it's like I will
always remember like this Indescribable
feeling of like
you know like because I've never felt
that word like I'm on stage you know
like I don't know what I'm supposed to
say yeah it's almost a reminder from you
to you of like this person these people
are fair they're seriously important to
me like I do actually care what not just
what they think you know not just that
they think highly of me because I said
the right words at a wedding but like I
really do want to communicate to them
like this is so special for me to be
here you know like yes if only words
really even could like you know not not
just could I access them or could I put
them in the right Cadence and Rhythm
properly with the right you know
tonality it's like if there was even the
words to express it like I just you know
you want to make sure these people know
that you love them and this is important
to you yeah later on you're like editing
yourself you're like man I should have
said this or whatever it is yeah no no
like I'm I'm at peace with it um but
it's funny like his his fiance or his
wife now was just like wow like Will's
really nervous and it's funny because
like he told me that like you know weeks
or months later like Nikki was like yeah
wow I was nervous
um and I was like dude I didn't realize
how nervous I was gonna be like you know
what I mean like it was it was funny
um it was a great experience since
um I mean I've DJ'd
I mean probably 40 to 50 weddings um and
I've been to you know at least 10 10 to
15 just just attending
um and something I always say or I
always um if I don't have the
opportunity to say it if I'm not not in
a position if I'm just an attendee I'm
not going to go give advice to the best
man but if I'm uh you know the DJ
handing the mic to the to the best man
hey you're going to start it off or the
the Bridesmaids are made of on or
whatever like my my little piece of
advice is always dude just just speak
from the heart like don't worry about
trying to say the right things just you
know this person probably as well as
anybody in this room just show that like
you you know this person speak from the
heart and usually that's that's one
place of uh wedding I never loved DJing
weddings there's there's a few things
about them that are strange to me
um but that's one thing that I really
love about about DJing weddings is
getting front row seats for the speech
like the yeah whether it's the best man
or or the maid of honor or even just
like you know someone's 12 year old
nephew said yeah that mic and he says
something that he's kind of crying
through it but it's the most adorable
thing he doesn't really say much but you
know what he's trying to say and it's
beautiful you know it's a good speech
that's just someone speaking from their
perspective or that or their heart is
that's great yeah it's the best it's a
it is a tough thing to do though like I
think I hear more like I because I feel
like this summer is like the covid
makeup of weddings you know what I mean
I think we've had five or six weddings
this spring and summer
um
and I you know I I feel like you hear
more like Rocky Top speeches than you do
really good ones you know
um which again my my speech was at the
start of the season so uh now here we
are in you know September and I like I
feel good about it like I've heard some
I've heard some tough best dance
features this summer in the maid of
honest yeah oh yeah yeah I'm feeling
pretty good I'm feeling pretty good dude
um but no I I can imagine like being a
DJ I I like would be a weird predicament
you know because like everyone knows
each other right like outside of like
the servers and this but like you're
kind of this intimate host where you're
like more involved but you don't really
know anymore it's kind of like a
interesting predicament to to be in
yeah because it is this innately
um yeah it is innately sentimental
um because everybody knows each other
and it's combining together of families
like everybody in some way knows either
the brighter the group ideally that's
how that's how a wedding is going to be
unless there's a couple you know
Crashers or whatever
um and so for me to anything for me to
interrupt their time and for them for me
to say whatever you guys are talking
about pause for a second and look at me
is already this like almost the audacity
of this [__] like like this is a
you know almost a religious spiritual
experience of us intertwining these two
families together or whatever and this
person's interesting so I you know I'm
always like uh cognizant of being you
know light with my word and trying to be
very
um particular you know there's the side
of me that I can be goofy and funny but
um I don't tap into that too much unless
I know the bride and groom or I know
like if I've had a chance to like meet
some of the parents or or something you
know I'll I'll crack a couple jokes but
there's a there's a fine line like I
have some friends who are DJs who uh who
like go pretty heavy with like the jokes
on the mic and I'm like man I don't know
so uncle's gonna point you in the face
it's like my sister's planning a wedding
right now she's getting married in
November maybe she's like the sixth one
we're going to um but it's like
stressful like be like people are out
there like I don't want to say their
best and their worst but it's like you
know emotions are high like it's
emotions are high people are getting
wasted like people are spending ungodly
amounts of money like it's a it's a
little like Powder Keg sometimes like a
whole wedding
um so when you have like I know when I
go to a wedding and I I love like
obviously knowing everyone I also love
like being the plus one and not knowing
anyone when you go to a wedding and it's
like both sides Good Vibes and it's like
you run into this guy in the bathroom
like oh man excuse me yeah and it's like
old somebody's like oh yeah but like
when it's like good it's it's really
good dude it's I love a good wedding
yeah yeah it's a it's it's a thing of
beauty it's um you know it's it's one of
the Traditions that uh our civilization
has kept around our culture has kept
around that is like there's some
weirdness about it because you know
we're kind of a post-religious um
community and it is a religious you know
ceremony so I think we're still our
generation is kind of finding our way
around like how to how to find meaning
and make meaning of like the vows we're
saying in in that sort of thing but um
yeah I think uh something I have learned
myself with weddings
probably not going to do too much more
of them because like I said I just I
don't love them you know it's it
probably won't do too many more but I do
feel that I have gotten actually
decently good these days at them just by
my demeanor like by being chill like by
being relaxed like any questions I have
any like make sure all of my ducks are
crazy in order before I even get to that
venue for the rehearsal in like my chill
calm demeanor of like yeah we got that
no problem cool I'll do that at this
time yeah I got you that seriously rubs
off like if like I said like you know if
you have if you're a host of a party and
you're all stressed out and everybody
comes over like there's something about
that energy that proliferates and now
it's kind of just anxiety all over and
if you're in a place of you know I'm a
host a lot of the times as a DJ at a
wedding especially and my calm demeanor
is I mean you could sense it through the
damn mic through the airwaves like
everything I say the way in which I say
it
um how sweaty I am how much I'm running
around if I'm just walking I'll get
linked to my next place it's it really
says a lot about like how things are
going behind the scene beans and so the
bride and groom don't have to be like oh
[__] are things going bad like they can
just be present and I could say hey it's
3 15. we're gonna head over here come on
you know so yeah that's the art of it is
being calm in in your profession in a
lot of ways for sure and yo so you just
saying that I made a connection so
remember I was talking about like
holding Betty and like giving off these
feelings through my fingertips and my
hands like this love and caring like I
can't communicate with her verbally yet
right so I'm like you know I we make a
joke or I make a noise so like what I
just did is like what you're doing at a
wedding and trying to give off these
calm Vibes like it's like almost like
that's what I'm trying to do through my
hands or through my demeanor or through
my smile
um but it is whether it's a baby or a
bride and groom and a you know
bridezilla and a stressful wedding
situation like you can you can truly
like you know make waves in a healthy
positive manner with just the way you
the way you conduct business the way you
you handle things
cool thank you for for making that
explanation because I just know what I'm
doing with my babies it's good it's good
it's healthy yeah um
yeah um so yeah we're trying to like
plan a wedding and it's like it's it's
bananas like the whole like you know
it's crazy
um but what we've settled on
um and this is like again like new age
you know not super religious so we're
basically inviting people to our
allotment in Las Vegas right so what
we're gonna so what we're gonna do is
like we're gonna fly out on like a
Wednesday Thursday
um we're gonna do like cool pictures in
the desert her in a dress me in a badass
suit
um my sister's uh Beyonce future husband
he's a wedding photographer um he's
awesome so they're gonna fly out early
Lana let Crystal's sister is Gonna Fly a
little early like we're trying to figure
out Benny like you know whether she
flies with the parents or whatever but
fly out there get some badass pictures
get like an Elvis like drive through
little wedding chapel like ceremony
thing
um really simple kind of silly like you
know play into the vagueness of it and
then Friday do like a family happy hour
kind of like catering you know simple
party like you know that's where we'll
kind of say our vows thank you for
making the Trek out here like kind of
pose it as like you need a getaway come
to Vegas celebrate with us on Friday
night and then Saturday we're gonna get
like Cabanas and bottles and spend too
much money at like a pool party and
invite all of our friends
and that'll be like you know I guess
we're asking a lot because it's like a
multiple day like you know almost like a
like an Indian style wedding but um dude
it's going to be a fraction of the price
that's perfect it's going to be so laid
back and like fun
um and it was actually Crystal's idea
because we've been like looking at these
venues and we're looking at like
45 000 for like a cheap wedding or like
60 000. yeah dude and that's like that's
like cheap cheap so she's like she's
been trying to get her to like you know
oh what friends do I choose to try to
fly over for you know from the west
coast and just dude it just becomes it
like do you you probably got to a place
where like do we have two weddings one
for the West Coast one for the East
totally and then it was like let's not
let's not even like do it like let's
just go to the courthouse get married
like let's not even spend the money and
you know whatever let's not um can you
still see me sorry my phone um but uh
yeah we were like we went through that
all those emotions of like let's not do
this but like I wanted I wanted to do
something you know I think there's
something
there's something there's something in
that tradition something that I wanted
to do like I wanna I wanna say some vows
in front of our friends and family of
like my love for this woman I think that
um I think she deserves that and I think
that um
I think it's something that I you know
we want to do I think she'll actually
struggle to find her words more than me
but I'm so interested
to see what she would possibly say
um but that's like that's not only
that's our like that's our you know 2022
kind of had the baby you know didn't do
things in a traditional sense but it's
like you know what like come come elope
with us get a weekend getaway you know
um you know Friday night we're gonna
have a little happy hour thing and then
Saturday you know get wasted pool party
yeah that sounds amazing that sounds way
fun I think that's I think yeah
yeah and also like Vegas kind of Vegas
makes it easy for her like West Coast
family and like from Philly to Vegas
like you know you can still get a cheap
flight like so there's always flights
going to Vegas so
um yeah I I we're gonna have to figure
out like the baby and families like we
might just stick like a like her her mom
maybe my parents like you know like in a
sick Airbnb and kind of make that like
home base for like everything
um
so yeah we're gonna we're gonna figure
out all those like little details but I
kind of like I like I like the planning
and the and the the struggle of the the
whole organization so man yeah I really
like that I think that's not only a good
idea but um you know what you said about
valves like kind of wanting to you know
set some vows and say them you know I
think there is
I thought about valves a lot actually
um
I had before Shailene and I split like a
few months before I had proposed and so
I was thinking a lot about
um like
like wedding because weddings I'm very
aware like you know there's no magic
that happens without the participants
you know it's not that just because you
say these words there's like magical
laws of the universe right up there with
gravity that make these things perfect
that go through sickness and health
that's just gonna happen I'll have to
try it's very much um I think I kind of
like as I got older and as I was going
to propose or as I proposed and as I was
like trying to think of what I would say
in my own vows I started really thinking
of the power of you know the spoken word
you know what we say is spells and as
much as I'm a rambler and stumble over
my words I think that there's power in
uh
like writing something that's very true
that you can read back and be like you
know what I can do that and that would
be really hard to do that would be
probably the hardest thing I would ever
do is devote to these things on this
piece of paper till the day I die but
I'm willing to do that and I would love
to do that you know I think there's you
can create your own magic in writing
your own vows or even not even just
writing them but like reading other vows
and seeing like you know what through
sickness and health and all these other
things I'm going to do that like in the
other person making that agreement too I
mean there really is some super powerful
magic of sorts that can arise out of
that and you guys could really get
through so much more if you really
remember in each moment that when it
gets hard of your vows like what what
did I agree to because when you could
reach back into your vows later on in
life in your marriage when things are
hard then you could say it gives you an
answer for that problem like yes it's
tough but I have to keep going because I
agreed to this or whatever it is you
know it's I think I think there's a lot
of power in vows man I think it's really
yeah and I think that's why personally I
like want to write mine myself
um just because I think they'll like
they'll hold more water for me you know
it'll like if I do spend the time
designing you know that collection of
words to you know to say in sickness and
health right to like capture that in my
own brain and mind and heart and body
and soul like I think it it's for me
just means something you know means a
little bit more
um rather than kind of just repeating
that thing like if I can if I can
somehow not completely fall apart
emotionally and like communicate this to
like her and any any of our loved ones
that that wanted to be there and could
be there and also like the loved ones
from Generations before that are no
longer with us right like if you can tie
in the magic of life and death and you
know till death do you part like I think
you know you're kind of you're I'm not
only honoring that person but you're
honoring like your family and you know
the union of these two families like
it's oh that's like the thread of
embodiment you know that's like really
trying to find that way it's not just
the words themselves it's not just you
say these and they magically open up a
you know Abracadabra the doors open and
you are granted access it's like how can
I really embody what's being said here
like the words themselves aren't aren't
powerful but me saying them in truth is
so very powerful you know and and also
I'll say if you do uh completely
emotionally break down and start crying
during your vows you're loved too that's
okay too yeah yeah for sure I'm sure
it's okay to do that definitely
definitely
um nah yeah I can't I it's funny like we
I was planning on asking Crystal to
marry me
um and then you know I was like I'm not
dragging my feet with the ring but like
you know it's a it's a whole thing
um so I was just kind of like you know
taking my time um and I knew that's what
I wanted but I was like I don't think
she's in a rush I'm not in a crazy rush
and then we found out that we were
pregnant
um and that was like that was a wild
experience because
um she was like it was like a Friday and
she was like Hey I feel like different
and uh I was like really she's like yeah
I think so we bought a pregnancy test it
was like a Friday night and I was like
can I just get one more weekend like
just so immature right like can I should
I just be can I just not deal with the
reality for one more weekend and again
like I think that's like me knowing
myself right just like let me let me
just be let me be a kid again right like
let me just be a kid for one more
weekend and then it was like that Monday
or Tuesday of that following week
um I think I was dropping her off at
work so we were both home in the morning
like doing breakfast and she was like oh
my God we got the practice test like
yeah let's do it she peed on the stick
and then dude like an hour and a half
went by like we both completely forgot
about it and then she was like oh my god
let's go check it out they ran into the
back bathroom I was pregnant and we both
started like laughing and giggling with
like no plan or no like you know what I
mean like we knew we could do it like
but it was like this we were not
expecting this thing here we are um and
here we are so then I was like okay in
my head I was like all right the
engagement's on hold right like let me
like let's let's attack this Challenge
and do the baby thing
um and then at some point like over the
summer into like early fall
I was like you know what like I don't
know why
these two things are not independent of
one another you know
um and I know Crystal didn't like need
me to like hey will you be my wife one
day like but I just felt like it spoke
it kind of said some things that I
couldn't not that I couldn't say it I'm
pretty good with like discussing my
feelings and stuff but I felt like
you know it wasn't it wasn't other
people's impression of her of her being
a pregnant woman not wearing a ring like
you know what I mean but like all those
things like those I you know I don't we
don't care what other people think yeah
a little bit more the
right right and it's like it's just like
you know what like I I was feeling this
way beforehand and now I'm not all of a
sudden not feeling this way I'm feeling
this way even more like I'm feeling this
is going to be the greatest challenge
ever but it's it's it's a challenge that
I want to do with you and like I want
you to be my wife but like I this isn't
on hold anymore sort of you know what I
mean and I would like she didn't need it
but I like like got back to like you
know getting the ring and designing it
and doing that whole thing
um and then it was really cool because
we have these pictures you know again my
my sister's fiancee
I had them kind of like they they met me
one morning and I was like hey I'm gonna
top question here tomorrow morning like
what do you think you think you guys can
be like hiding and like get you know get
the moment like when it happens and they
did and it was amazing but like she's
got this like little baby bump you know
and we're like we're in like in
sweatpants getting like you know coffee
in the morning
um and it was just like a really
beautiful moment but
um yeah it was just funny kind of the
way the timelines went down and how I
was like all right that's on hold like
let me attack that and it kind of helped
me understand myself that I like I do
like to like all right like let me focus
on this like let me let me and you know
life's not like that
um so it's interesting so we've engaged
for
uh you know a while now since like last
November it'll be engagement for a year
in November and I think like you know
hopefully sometime early early summer of
next year uh we'll be we'll be looking
to lock in our wedding date and
everything yeah amazing it's so cool how
it all falls into place you know and it
sounds like that moment you just
mentioned like that you know she had a
little baby bump and it sounds like that
might have been a day or a moment where
you're like damn this is all all right
you know yeah what uh other people that
had gotten engaged like dude you like
you black out and like you know and I I
don't know if that was your experience
or whatever but like I truly like I I
grabbed her hand and I started going
down I was like hey you know I love you
right and she was like what did I do
like she thought she like you know so it
didn't get off to like the hottest start
but then I just like got down to one day
and I opened up this ring and I don't
know you know what I mean like I don't I
told her I loved her and like told her
that I wanted to you know be with her
exactly what you said though I had no
idea dude no
um and then uh you know we just were
just both crying and then like my sister
and her fiance got right up next to us
and I could hear the shutter of the
camera and I knew they were there right
and um you know Bella's with us like our
little dog she's like jumping and like
they're like right next to him like look
like look who it is and like she looks
and she's like surprised that they're
there and she's just like weeping and it
was like a beautiful moment
um and then she was like are we getting
coffees and I'm like no like all all of
your friends are at our house I mean
like my family and her friends were like
all right already at our house with like
brunch so they had like set everything
up and like mimosas
she said no
yeah she's like well I just need some
time alone to think about it uh well all
of our family and friends are at the
house so yeah well you uh will you tell
my parents they're they're at your house
yeah it's a beautiful thing Man it
really is cool to see you know
um like I said we're at this time where
Traditions are they're just looked at
differently you know and even things
like marriage I think we just think
about things differently than our
parents age
um so it's very cool to hear
you know uh you know good friends of
mine and and people my age and
like-minded individuals be able to still
find like Beauty in this thing that
sometimes feels a little bit different
than us it feels like yeah it's kind of
like out of our it's not like weddings
don't feel like us in a lot of ways but
in a lot of ways they can you know in a
lot of ways like it's still cool to you
know clearly there's a lot of beauty and
a lot of like specialness that you guys
are very much tapping into it's all
still there you know maybe it's a little
bit yeah for sure well it's funny it's
funny it's like one of my dad's buddies
uh was just like you know you you made
an honest woman out of her good job you
know what I mean it was like
and I I didn't say like well that's not
why I did it you know what I mean but
like he was like proud of me that I
popped the question because I got her
pregnant you know what I mean it was
like such like an ass backwards way of
thinking about it like that's not how I
was thinking about it but like you know
it was like that old way of thinking
with the Traditions that are supposed to
be done you know properly and like you
know I was just I was just listening to
my body you know what I mean I was
listening to the situation I was like
vibing with Crystal and like you know
this this life we're building together
it was like you know what like why why
why am I treating these like the
engagement and the baby is like this one
needs to be done now that this has
happened I gotta hold off and it's like
no dude like that's you were doing that
you wanted to do that like do that you
know like it's good like it'll be good
you know just like listening to like
that that intuition
um oh yeah I think I think I had asked
you guys uh when you were in Austin but
what's your do you have like a 5 10
20-year kind of idea plan are you guys
like
um
yeah so uh uh it's not obviously like
nothing set in stone
um but we I wrote down I wrote down like
the years you know what I mean I went
across and did like 22 23 I did five
years and just like wrote them across I
think I did 15 or 20 years and then I
just wrote in each year like
you know what I want to achieve for the
family you know I mean so it's like okay
we got we have a small row home in
Philly that I'd like to hold on my plan
is like hold on to the row home in
Philly rent it out eventually
um and then get a house in The Burbs
where we can like raise Bennett good
school district growing up I never
thought I'd go back to Jersey
um taxes are crazy but there's really
good Public Schools I always thought I'd
go on the other side of Philadelphia
like Montgomery County Chester County
like the counties outside of Philly on
the West Side
um but like now like like I think we'll
end up in Jersey like I just my family's
close Crystal's mom's actually moving to
Jersey
um now that Crystal's sister is living
in Philly like her mom's out there with
Lily and like they're making the moves
to come over
um which is amazing yeah it's actually
it's amazing it's bananas and it's I'm
so proud of her mom for doing it for a
million reasons yeah I'm with you there
yeah um so anyway it's like I just think
we're gonna end up in Jersey close to my
parents close to her mom um so like
that's like on the that's like in the
five year plan like that's probably like
the biggest thing is like you know earn
enough save enough so we can purchase a
you know a reasonable you know house in
a good school district and still keep
the current house so hopefully I don't
have to sell this to buy buy the new one
that's like The Five-Year Plan and then
it's like honestly like it's like you
know get the wedding done go on a
honeymoon
um you know places we want to see or
visit
um and then like you know
I don't know what else is on there it's
kind of just like travel like
achievement work you know I'd like to
I'd like to I applied for this promotion
at the job
um and I haven't been here that long I
was kind of like it was really good of
the company to give me the freedom and
the confidence to like apply for this
job but I was like [__] it I'm gonna
apply for it and I interviewed and I
interviewed well uh but they gave it to
someone else that had more tenure
um that like it made total sense to me
and I kind of agreed with the situation
uh but I know that they're going to be
it's a young company that we're growing
so
um I'd like to you know get one of those
jobs it's going to be the next five
years yeah for sure and I would be I
would I would be great for the role as
well so um that's like another something
else that's in my five year plan yeah
um and then you know I can't go go ahead
sorry no no you gotta keep going I was
gonna say I can't wait to like talk to
my daughter and find out what she wants
to do you know what I mean like maybe
it's like go to this go to the zoo in
2024 you know and I don't really like
supporting zoos because they're [__]
up they're like you know jails for
animals but you know she wants to go
check it out like I wanna I wanna go
there with her so right yeah this whole
plan is based off of like you know it's
gonna obviously change up actually
develops a personality and like yeah
you're complaining on what you and
Crystal want but then it's gonna be like
like what it's been at what you know so
uh yeah that that's the beauty of it but
I do think that it's very wise and very
smart of you to have some sort of
outline of your next five years or ten
years whatever it is because
um it's it's something that that I
I kind of have ups and downs with
because uh I kind of go through these
phases of
I'm at this just lift your legs up and
let the River float you down I have a
lot of those things where I'm just like
I don't really know what my plan is I
don't really know what I'm trying to
achieve here but I'm just my ears and
eyes and and you know my ears and eyes
are open to Opportunities so I don't
really know exactly where I'm gonna go
but I'm floating around and entrusting
the world trusting the universe as it as
it is but there's also something I
discover I think there's there's Seasons
I think there is times to float around
and then I think there's times to where
like I'm pretty sturdy with where I'm at
so like let's send some direction
towards it what's what's the saying the
um the the ship with no direction or the
the sailboat with no Direction favors no
wind
or something like that uh basically like
like whatever win you're trying to catch
doesn't matter if you don't even know
whether you're trying to go north south
east or west so there there is some
beauty and at least kind of having an
outline of I want to achieve these
things let's see where the wind can take
us
yeah what is like what is it's like
success is where like opportunity and
preparation meet right or like something
like that right yeah like you have to
you have to like you have to mix it up
you know you have to like again that's
why I think like my advice early on is
like know what who you are right like
know who you are and what you like and
as soon as you do that which is not an
easy task but as soon as you better
understand yourself you can start to
figure out like what your plan is
because you know what you want or what
you like you know and life will throw
you a million curve balls but if you at
least like have some stuff that you are
interested in or like to do or you know
what makes you happy and know who you
are then you can like then you can at
least put together a rough out a rough
outline you know
yeah yeah I think that's a powerful tool
is know who you are know thyself that's
uh yeah I think that that's my like
biggest advice I'm sorry I'm just trying
to get through a power source here so I
apologize
probably dying out yeah yeah but we're
good to go
um I mean we're getting fairly up there
um I did I was actually going to ask you
uh you know basically advice to your
younger self like if you had if you had
opportunity to open a window of you at
this age you experiencing what you're
going through now to kind of just like
have have a conversation with your
younger self maybe 16 maybe he's 18 like
and he actually listens and might
reciprocate that advice like what do you
think he would say I would
yeah something like you're like
you're not as hot [__] as you think you
are you know what I mean like dude
dude you're an insecure like little you
know [__] right like you think you got
it all figured out you don't
um and you know no one that's uh that's
a great like you you think you got it
all figured out you don't but like
really nobody has it all figured out
right nobody does right yeah right it so
that's cool but stop acting like you do
you know
um because when you can
chill out and like you know accept it
accept who you are you know you're like
you're a much better human you know if
you know everything you've got nothing
left to learn
right to put yourself in dude can you
imagine can you imagine like just yeah
right like whatever okay any books I
read they cannot change me I know it
yeah dude it was yeah it was it was nice
to hear you talk about that guy that sat
on the bench for two years what who was
that what was that
gentleman's name oh Eckhart Tolle
um yes yeah I don't know I don't know
who that is have you ever heard of him
um so yeah he's a spiritual teacher he
teaches very um he's he's a non-dualism
teacher
um so kind of I think I think immune
kind of say buddhism-ish
um a little bit of Hinduism his is kind
of like the nature of the self um it's
kind of a lot of core teachings have you
read much Alan Watts
um no no it's another philosopher but uh
he's not so much spiritual but uh I'm
kind of the Core teaching of Eckhart
Tolle is
um like seeing through the illusion of
the self like you're not a separate self
like you like we have an ego but we're
kind of a we're a little bit of a soul
having a human experience and vice versa
in in many ways but he so his the way he
came to it though
um if I recall correctly he was
committing suicide so he had a
accidental
he was like trying to kill himself but
he didn't fully die and it basically
like killed his ego so he had a
near-death experience an nde if you ever
heard of people talk about those and it
woke him up to the the trueness of
himself like the things that um you know
the the people we we have read you know
Jesus Christ and the Buddha and uh uh uh
you know uh all these other you know
enlightened beings that we hear through
all these stories they are basically
humans that I've had
um an experience that allows them to see
through on like a con consistent all the
time level
um the illusion of the self and so
they're basically residing
um in this area of of knowing of they're
sitting in this area of Consciousness
um
it's kind of the same place we're all
trying to get through if you hear people
talk about Enlightenment I want to
become enlightened they are kind of the
thing that people who are wanting to be
enlightened get or want to get to there
really is no arrival and it's based off
of your own karmic predicament you will
you will not be you know reach these
levels of samadhi or not but
um yeah so Eckhart Tolle he's now a
spiritual teacher he sits on stages he's
very if you've never listened to him
he's very frustrating to listen to
because he talks
the self
is laughs
I'm gonna lose like he speaks very like
that it's frustrating but it's also he
says things that like they're um he
speaks in Koons which have you heard of
Koons koas like I said he speaks a lot
in those things and they're kind of if
you listen without over intellectualize
what intellectualizing what he's
speaking about
um they bring you to these places that
cohans are trying to to allow you to see
so he has he has a book called
um uh
[Music]
be here now
I think it's B here now but I would
recommend that book that's great for
anybody to be here now
I will I will check it out do some
research but yeah I just like
I'll I'll look it up I'll find it um I
just like the idea yeah I like the idea
of you talking about like you're like
sitting on the bench right like what
that meant him sitting on the bench for
two years right and like your time
at the house in Castle Rock like you
know sitting on the bench right
metaphorically and I started to think
about like my time in like Florida like
sitting on the bench like getting my
[__] together like understanding myself
in the world and like you know what was
going on
um I'd like another time in my life and
maybe it's retirement maybe it's old age
but I would like to like sit on the
bench metaphorically for a little while
and like as like a more complete person
right like not striving so hard for like
change and growth and to fix you know
um I'd like to like just sit I think
that would be nice to like see what sort
of epiphany and like life's lessons come
with like
you know just just sitting and listening
and watching yeah no absolutely I mean
they write about the um
the so like in the in the illuscinian
Mysteries uh they basically write about
this this write-up passage that a lot of
young people would go through
um back in like the Roman days and um
essentially they would say if you die
before you die when you die you will not
die and it's kind of this experience you
can have
um you know and you're sitting on the
bench is kind of like coming to some
sort of bridge Bridging the Gap between
um like seeing through the illusion of
who you thought yourself to be but uh if
you die before you die that's the ego
that dies but the awareness The Observer
that we all are this constant uh
observes observes the dissolution of
this of this separate ego and so there's
things that you can you can sit in that
for a lot of times like you said like
when you're older it'd be nice to just
kind of like really read a lot of these
books and just or you know just sit
there and experience that like a really
experience Stillness because it kind of
is the core of what we are as human
beings but it's it's so elusive it's the
perfect word for it you know just like
the illusory self this this silence that
persists is also very Elusive and hard
for us to there's too much going on all
the time and our stories our our
exacerbating or every movement and why
we do things and we're always thinking
and we're identifying with thoughts and
all these things that the silence the
Observer the constant awareness that is
there throughout all of those things the
thing that sees all of that that
observes everything that happens you can
get in tune with that you can sit with
that where it's just that and that's
yeah yeah
well you're still sitting on the bench
rather even if you're laying in the
grass under a tree and just met dating
like you know you could like yeah the
the grass is there the trees there like
that stuff can can fade away and you can
um go to that place but like I'd like to
spend some more time there I think
um
you know I I think so like that's like
that's why I'm a fan of like
psychedelics you know like that that
that death of the death
because then you say well you said again
the Roman
uh yeah yeah if you die before you die
when you die you will not die right
right like that's a that's an acid trip
to me you know like have you done and
I'm not we can edit this if you're not
if you wouldn't like to talk about it
have you done um psychedelics at all
yeah yeah yeah for sure
um like obviously not much you know
recently but like definitely in my in my
early days
um I experimented a little bit in
college and nothing crazy like I think
it's
I think it's super duper healthy to have
that ego death
um
and to kind of like I know like I feel
like completely connected you know for
me they're like nature nature daytime
obviously everyone has like their own
experiences but
um yeah they're they're the best you
know they're the best of the best
they're the best yeah yeah it's it's for
me I know like I've heard some people
kind of like discuss them and like you
know kind of um
successfully capture some of those
things I've never really been able to do
that uh
but yeah there's a
there's a uh there's like a childlike
wonderment that uh rushes over me in you
know in a in a trip that uh it's the
best I guess yeah yeah I would very much
like to I mean how you talked about when
you're older it'd be nice to just you
know sit on the bench so to say it would
be nice to just you know you're you're
60 years old and you just take five
years and just do mushrooms every day
yeah it would become a shrub for a bit
dude uh dude I'd love to be a turnip and
a shrug for a little while and be sick
just sit there no yeah um like yeah like
mushrooms and hiking and you know
trying to see it all from it through a
different lens definitely yeah I mean
it's crazy I think California or San
Francisco yesterday just decriminalized
um
mushrooms really
yeah I'm pretty sure I saw San Francisco
yesterday earlier this week see that's a
step in the right direction I mean it's
it's happening yeah yeah it's it's
happening it's uh yeah I am a little bit
afraid of the um capitalistic arm that's
like you know reaching its way right in
through the middle of all of these
things but it's just an inevitable
capitalism meets everything
um but I do yeah but if you look if you
look what's happened with like marijuana
right like when we were kids you had to
buy a bag and you had to sneak around
and now like you know like you go you
know you go to the store and you can
like you know you can literally tell
them like even if you're a novice smoker
you can be like hey I have anxiety but I
don't want to be too it to be too
psychoactive or like you can tell them
what you're looking for and then they
can help that's so like yeah yeah and
that's like the cat that is the
capitalist arm right that's like one of
the byproducts of like real money
getting into marijuana
um which I'm sure there was Growers back
in the day that you could have done that
but like me on the East Coast like we
never had the availability so just now
like in the last few years where like
there's you can legally you know go buy
weed
um it's crazy so I'm hoping like despite
you know the the pitfalls of capitalism
um I'm hoping like the mushrooms can
start like dude there's my buddy got
these mushrooms and like during a
beautiful packaging and it like has the
suggested dosage for a micro dose and
then if you want to like kind of wow out
a little bit it tells you and then if
you want to like see God it gives you
like another dosage so like that sort of
stuff like when we were kids like you
eat mushrooms out of a bag right you're
like oh let me do like a couple stems a
couple calves and like hope everything
goes well you can't dude that was the
exciting God you could see some visuals
like your night's going to be very
different based off of your experience
though dude I one time my buddy had a
trash bag like just a giant bag of them
um and I pulled out the biggest cap ever
in front of like again like young will
like trying to like be somebody like I
pulled out this gigantic cap and stem
and like nine of my friends are like
smoking blunts like looking at me and
I'm like I ate the whole thing and then
like you know I was like sweating and
losing my [__] for you know the next
like you know I don't remember exactly
the time frame but like for an hour I
was like really really like lost in the
sauce and had like yeah I didn't need
that you know what I mean like maybe I
did like maybe some good you know good
came out of it
um man but yeah like the hilarious thing
you're taking a huge mushroom caps
because you want to be somebody like
it's so funny because it's like this ego
this experience in many ways yeah right
I think you're right I think the um the
the beauty that comes with a lot of this
like you know the new psychedelic
Renaissance that we're experiencing is
we now are knowledgeable about it like
you you would now know and you would
recommend to other people like hey if
you have an opportunity to have a sack
full of mushrooms and you're not in a
place where
but like if you're just at a party where
everybody's drinking and hanging out
maybe it's not the best place to take
mushrooms you know set and setting is so
big with a lot of these things even weed
even cannabis even Edibles
um people you know we have enough
information and knowledge about it that
we can not only put that on the
packaging that we're selling these
things but it could just be another
known thing in the Zeitgeist of doing
psychedelics it's like like you're not
going to let your friend take five grams
of mushroom before it goes to the you
know the Top Gun movie premiere because
you know he's gonna [__] freak out
right five grams we're gonna do it at my
place and we're gonna get pillows and
we're gonna wash each other's hands and
we're gonna listen to this album and
like whatever hippie [__] you plan that
out because you know exactly the
experience that's going to happen when
you write this amount
right no it's and dude you said it set
and setting like it is that is the
that's the key to like any psychedelic
experience
um yeah I mean even yeah that's what I
say I I repeat that I'm someone I'm a
I'm a a pretty heavy cannabis user to
this day still but I you know when I was
going through all that stuff in Castle
Rock and Washington where I was going
through you know like I said digging up
all this childhood trauma and stuff I
was I was smoking a lot and I think that
um it did allow doors to be open that
couldn't have been open with without it
but like
but again it's a tool it's you know is
people call it plant medicine which is
kind of you know people roll their eyes
at calling psychedelics or or LSD or any
of that stuff plant Medicine sure there
is some eye rolling but it really is I
think it's worth treating like a
medicine like you could really unlock
some places in your psyche or beyond
your psyche even rather uh with with
these tools but it's a it's a medicine
you got to be careful you know this yeah
definitely I um
I uh every time I have like a like
really tripping experience
um I like I'll have a like a 10 minute
period where I want to like call my
parents and tell them I love them and
then like it breaks my heart because
they're kind of from the generation of
like you know like don't don't do drugs
like if you eat mushrooms like you jump
out a window
um and I gave my dad that book The
Michael polian um how to change your
mind I mean have you read that I haven't
read it but I know it exists yeah
there's like a Netflix like yeah there's
like a Netflix show I think that's like
kind of grasp like the book in a Netflix
show
um yeah I think well yeah I gave it to
him and I don't I don't think he ever
finished it but I think it started to
kind of change his mind a little bit
um right like uh just like getting him
to kind of wrap his head around like
it's a tool right it's not this like
naughty like don't do this thing or
you're gonna be forever changed like and
that can happen
um but that's always like Don known's
always been like the fun part like
that's always gotten me going you know
the these you know who knows what's
gonna happen
um like you know I we don't have
schizophrenia in our family so like I
kind of felt confident the first couple
times like all right I'm not I'm not
gonna break like I'm not gonna like I
might feel like I'm never going back
um but that's like a normal feeling you
know like you're gonna go back to normal
um yeah well uh Joe Rogan has said with
with uh Edibles he's talked about like
you feel like you're gonna die but
you're not gonna die you feel like
you're gonna die but you know he always
says he loves he loves them on planes
and I like to that sounds like yeah
right right so I like if I have a long
flight like I'll like I'll smoke a
little bit before you know like can just
you know pass out and you know have my
have my you know West East the West
Coast Flight and wake up and be like oh
it was great um just like kind of mellow
me out but I've done I've tried Edibles
on planes and that's like I don't sleep
I don't enjoy myself like I am to me
like eating's like it's a different it's
a different job yeah well so it's
actually five times more psychoactive
it's a it actually kind of creates a
different not only experience but kind
of creates a different drugs I think
because when it passes through your
liver it releases or
was it released five dimexal I don't
[__] know I heard someone else talk
about it but it is different drugs and
it's five times more psychoactive I
actually am not affected by Edibles I
don't have the gut you're one of those
you're one of those guys take a ton
although I never have taken like all
right bro I'm taking 100 milligrams
let's go to the moon like I've never
done that so like dude we were down we
were down the yeah we were down the
beach like I guess Last Summer the
summer before one of the holiday
weekends we were at one of Crystal's
friends family's house and we're going
out on the boats all day and somebody
was like yo do you want an edible and uh
I was like yeah and they handed me one
gummy work and I was like
what is it at most 25 milligrams I'll
pop it in I'm showing it and then like
someone comes out and I'm like yo how
much how much were these they were like
ah like 125. wow I was like all right oh
my God okay this my day is going to be a
little bit different I've got about 20
minutes till uh I was like I'm not
driving the boat like no one needs me to
drive the boat all right at all I'll
figure it out and I was like supremely
stoned all day
um no I mean not all day I was kind of
back to normal by like dinner time but
it was like it was a definitely like a
five six hour like I'm I'm very we also
got we for Crystal's 30th we we flew out
to Seattle during covid rented a house
and we're just gonna like there's no
bars or anything were open like her
sister was still living out there we're
just gonna party and do our thing and
just hang out in the sick house and
Magnolia I think in the Magnolia section
of Seattle
and we all got covered so and everyone
felt like [__] so we were just like
actually living out there yeah we were
supposed to meet up I actually remember
this yes and we were like it was crazy
because we were like stuck like we
didn't know like like none of us felt
comfortable like we couldn't get back on
a flight like knowingly having covid
everyone had symptoms everyone felt like
[__] for a couple days so we were like
all self-medicating with like 100 100 I
guess who would wake up and everyone
need 100 milligrams and we would just
watch movies and like melt into like the
couch and floor and it was like it was
actually very therapeutic and nice but
those two times like the highest I've
ever been on edible as you planned but
yeah not at all dude
I mean I I'm pretty sure my mom doesn't
listen to this um so forgive me for
talking about this but my mom actually
like within the last year had a crazy
edible experience this this poor woman
she told me she laughs about it now but
it was like crazy for her so she takes
these um she's had back surgeries and
stuff so she has like a little bit of
like uh pain that that kind of happens
most days and uh she you know after a
while she got away from the pain pills
like the orange pill bottles and she's
been taking like half a half a little
um not a gummy but like a hard candy or
something like that or maybe it's five
milligrams 10 milligrams Max well she's
been taking that for quite a while
she has this brand that she likes she
does pretty much every day she takes
like a half of these things she goes
about her day she feels pretty good
maybe she'll take another one before bed
or whatever uh but she was out of the
hard candies and so in the same brand
they had a chocolate of the same thing
and she took that
um and then she went to this poor thing
she basically went to the country club
and so she's in this place where it's
like you know a country club is just
what you expect yeah yes you know stuffy
and golf carts and you know we're uppity
and you know we have a couple martinis
but they probably don't get hammered or
anything I don't know how it goes really
this is country club but she's also in
this place and I say and I describe
Country Club it's not just like some
restaurant because my mom like she grew
up in like a very small town she was
like pretty country like a country club
is just not where she would find herself
even as a kid like let alone as an adult
but she happens to be she's dating this
new woman who goes to the country club a
lot so she's in this new experience
she's never dated a woman before either
so she's recently in this like just this
new world you know she's loving life
she's in this new world takes us edible
that she's normally used to taking she's
sitting there at the table and she
starts to like she's currently getting a
little high so she like leans over she's
like texting her her girlfriend fiance
now and she's like hey uh I'm feeling
that edible I normally don't feel but
I'm feeling edible and her fiance is
like okay cool like keep stalking and
she's like talking all these ladies
meeting all these nice ladies for the
first time she starts like tripping and
she starts she gets the point where
she's like Julian's over and I guess she
says I actually think I might pass out I
think I might faint I'm like tripping
out she faints at the [__] table from
an edible
um turns into this whole episode long
story short it turns into like my mom
gets paranoid and she's like she said
that she was like going through like
some like weird like old memory [__] was
coming up and she like didn't really
trust any of these ladies suddenly she's
in the kitchen tripping out they called
an ambulance like all of this [__] over
there
I know but uh it's she she laughs about
it now and like I've had a long
discussion with her about it you know
and but that is the thing we are dealing
with this um I feel bad I just like
exposed my mom she doesn't listen to the
podcast or anything but um
it's a good lesson it's a good lesson
for people to like hear I was I was
talking to her um what I know about the
process of even making Edibles like it's
probably I mean you think you know
imagine a kitchen in a pan in like you
know the the liquid that has the THC and
the stuff that makes you psychoactively
you know react as a human and maybe it
floats off the corner of the pan you
know and maybe like that corner of the
brownie is a [__] lot stronger than
this other Corner because gravity here
you know the weight when they mix it in
with the chocolate it's it's such a
thick substance that it doesn't mix
quite well and so you just you're just
kind of gambling sometimes with with
Edibles and I think maybe chocolate
might be a bigger gamble at this point
anywhere so
yeah I always try to tell like newer
people to like stay away from the bars
right like if it's a bar and you're
breaking off like a square for just the
reason you said what I think works
better is like the individual gummies
right so if it's like one gummy Works in
my head as a like from a factory
perspective I see it as like like you
know I mean it kind of like shoots in
like four spots and then it's like so I
mean even that concoction isn't totally
perfect
um but dude like I like you remember
eating brownies like when you're a kid
and like you could eat a brownie and be
totally fine then you can be a brownie
and be on Mars
um again like capitalism having like
more of a hand in it like has definitely
like kind of um standardized the doses
um
but yeah do we used to get these
chocolate bars back in the day that were
like so insanely inconsistent and we
were like you know early 20s so it was
like fun you would like break up a bar
and it would be like who is going to be
drooling on themselves you know like
which one of us and they were like hash
oil so they were like intense and we
were drinking you know 20 beers a night
back in those days like it was just the
true like college partying days but it
was like it was like a spin of roulette
of like who out of the four pieces of
the bar was gonna be like really messed
up it's crazy how uh you know careless
you are with with drugs and stuff when
you're a teen like think about like the
first time my first experience with with
Molly was one of my good friends took
Molly before school one day and I didn't
even know what it was and I was like
[__] with him like I was like I
realized that he was reacting to what I
was doing and I was like making fun of
him and like just making him have a
terrible trip like a complete [__]
but I didn't know any better yeah you
didn't know any better yeah and that's
how it was like you know after school
you get a bunch of as many four Locos as
your money can buy you get whatever weed
you can get your hands on and you you
explore you know and so yeah
we didn't do a ton of a ton of like
mushrooms or acid or anything when I was
a teen uh when I was in a later teen we
were doing a lot of like ecstasy and
stuff so that's another gamble but uh
yeah I mean it's all fun but you got to
be careful
yeah I was a little later to the game
like I smoked pot and stuff in like high
school but I like didn't really try
anything else until like you know the
for me like the experimental years of
like college and then like you know
first real job and post College
um that was kind of like my
experimenting and kind of figuring it
all out
um yeah it's well Duty like it's it's
crazy as a child how insanely Reckless
you are with your body drug like you
just you don't the VA your value of like
what this whole thing is is just not
exactly formulated yet you know yeah
yeah you just you just want to feel good
right now like you're not thinking about
yourself as a whole or like how this
experience might affect you later you're
just like cool I'll do that that's gonna
make me feel cool right now all right
let's feel cool right now
yeah like dude like driving around
smoking blunts like in the woods like
driving way too fast with a million
trees we're like you know what I mean
like you're just down this little like
country road flying like smoking like
it's like we're Invincible it's just
bananas
um and now like with having a child and
I know that that's that sort of behavior
is you know maybe a little far away on
the horizon it's like all right how do I
you know how do I
make this kid a little bit more mature
than I was where they're decision making
is a little bit
and I still enjoy themselves and you
know they still make the mistakes and
learn from them but like how do I
how do I make her a little bit more
respectful of like the value of life you
know maybe that's an impossibility but
it's like I'm trying to think that way
you know yeah I mean I think the art
with being a parent is you know whatever
whatever it looks like Benny when she's
14 she's gonna be stoned mobbing over in
a golf cart or something you know maybe
17. you should have some version of
exploring her Consciousness or having
fun a little bit too much fun with her
friends when she's a teen or something
and so it's the art of uh you know you
and Crystal as parents looking back to
how do I teach her teacher lessons that
are actually helpful how do I hear her
and see her for like hey I did pretty
much similar stuff so like I'm not
making you feel bad but like let's look
at the future like how do you take the
things that you didn't learn in that
moment or that you ignored that your
parents tried to teach you and try to
teach them a little bit better like
reach through with your own personal
experience yeah well I think like keep
telling them about your own personal
experiences like for me that's like a
difference I would think my parents were
like I'm not gonna like I never did any
like no dude I did it all like and I
will I will tell her I'll give her like
bits and pieces based on her age and
maturity but like I'm gonna like I'm
gonna tell her what I did you know like
I'm gonna if she asked me a question
like obviously within reason of like her
age I'm gonna be honest with her because
I think that that's how you like
cultivate in honest open relationship
you know it demystifies it too I think
it takes it yeah it's like ooh alcohol
to like yeah what do you want to know
about it I'd love to tell you anything
you would like to know about it from
Mike yeah definitely yeah open book
perfect
um yeah dude I I think that's like my
step and the other thing that I will do
differently about many things but like I
don't my parents always said like you
represent me right like you represent me
like you represent you know our last
name
um and you're an Andes and I'm like I'm
kind of gonna be like
you I
you don't owe me [__] [__] like I just
think like I you don't owe me anything
like I owe you you know and I think that
sort of disposition that like you're
representing yourself like you're living
for you
um like I think that for me is like a
distinction that I that I will will make
with her what do you think that is is
that like a legacy like you're so if you
if you want a child to like focus on
like their name like their like your
name holds holds Merit holds power is
that like focus on your legacy or like
what is that what because I didn't know
yeah I think so I think it's Legacy I
also think like I'm the oldest first
born son you know it's some like Game of
Throne [__] where it's like you know
you're and my father and I we share
first and last name we have different
middle names so I think that kind of
like there's old school whereas like I
told my dad because we didn't find out
Bennett's sex
um before she was born we like were
surprised which was fun and I encourage
anyone that's having a child to like be
surprised yeah because there's not many
surprises you can get herself and that
was like a true surprise
um but I I told my dad like if it's a
boy like I'm not naming him William
Andes and he was like what why like not
didn't get it I was like dude because
like not that I spent my entire life
like living
up to you or like looking up to you like
or trying to be you but like I want my
son to like do his own thing you know
like I'm there for him yeah yeah yeah
um and I was never like trying to fill
anyone's shoes but it was like that
whole thing of like you represent me you
represent this family like anything you
do in the outside world and I was like a
well-behaved like kid
um until I wasn't you know what I mean
until I got to puberty and you know my
mom like trying to like constrain me and
you know and I just like you know I was
all right I'm doing whatever I want I'm
gonna be a little crazy psycho um but
yeah
um I don't know how we got that in this
rabbit hole but yeah yeah no what I
think just
um you know we're talking kind of about
like Legacy and about how you know you
know your last name does hold some some
sort of Merit and I I look at that from
I don't know I I don't think I had
anything like that I mean my childhood
was was just different I think there was
um
I don't know I I'm just curious how I
operated differently than other people
not really
because I was always very individual but
I was never I'm a rhines like I was
never you know um like mine's mine's
very much me and I wonder like if I was
my dad's name's Jim if I was just Jim Jr
if I would have been a little bit more
like well what do we represent as orions
like what does orions do maybe I would
do the do things that my dad did just
because he did them and maybe they would
that wouldn't be the best thing for me
or something I don't know right or maybe
like you know now like after all the
work you've done you'd still hold some
like some negative feelings towards your
dad because you did have the same last
name and you know he he made some
mistakes when he was younger or whatever
like it's I it could be that much or it
could be nothing you know I we so we
named her
we took both of our middle names so my
middle name is Bennett uh Crystal's
middle name is Renee so we did Bennett
Renee Andes so her initials are bra bra
which like is nothing but like naming a
human is so like oh you probably think
about that right yes but so I like once
we kind of like we're like oh let's take
both of our middle names it's kind of
cool Bennett or call her Benny it's
little tomboyish like that's just where
we landed
um I was like nice like her initials are
bra like and I like I'm gonna give her
that nickname like when she's like eight
or nine on the soccer field I'm just
gonna start calling her bra and she's
gonna hate it and it's gonna be
hysterical and I'm gonna tell her like
she's gonna be like mad at me that I
like made her initials brought like dude
this whole thing this whole thing is
like super intense and super whatever
but like it's just it's funny dude like
let it keep it light keep it light
you'll enjoy it if you keep it light
like you did a dichotomy of life like
it's it's very long and it's life is
super short but it's also very long and
it's super intense and it's also super
like funny so yeah yeah yeah so so the
little like where the word play and the
little Giggles you gotta take them man
like yeah yeah like that's that's gonna
be your nickname on the soccer field of
this bra you know right it's so cool
though I feel like that's gonna be part
of her personality you know like what's
up bro
yeah what's up bro yeah exactly exactly
dude yeah that's the beauty of it
um man we're we're getting fairly up
here in time yeah dude dude I think you
tried to call it like 20 minutes ago and
I just kept ranting so no I I again I'm
in no rush um I I feel like to be honest
you and I could probably talk forever so
maybe we can do yeah yeah dude I would I
would love to do this again now that
we've like you know now that we've done
it once I would um I like talking to you
dude it's easy it's very easy and you're
uh you're a good good person to bounce
ideas off of
um I really came with like No Agenda
um which I think was like wonderful so
like I don't know maybe next time not
that I'll come with any agenda but I'll
come at least with like I want to bounce
these ideas off of you or something you
know no that's super fun I do that with
uh my friend Spencer who is uh he's just
like my My ultimate philosopher friend
like he he goes to college for like
philosophy and stuff but I just I'm just
a an armchair philosopher who's obsessed
with the act of philosophy and studying
on my own
um so him and I a lot of times we'll do
you know three three and a half hour
long podcasts just based off of like one
subject or like one book or one article
or one like hey we have this
philosophical thought about huntology
let's talk about that and like well I
mean it's just great so yeah we can we
can approach it with a subject so keep
that in mind just as you're living about
your life if there's something where
you're like man I think it'd be a dope
conversation to have with Jake just you
know make it 100
before I will yeah I'm uh this podcast
is very
I'm letting it be organic I'm not trying
to strangle it too much
um I I do have I have a lot of I think I
told you guys before I have a lot of
like guests just sitting in my inbox
that I just need to schedule like a lot
of really cool people that I pump to
have an opportunity to talk to you I
just
um the scheduling aspect of things is is
it's not only the the the act of like
emailing back and forth and scheduling
and talking to people's assistant and
emailing back six different times and
changing the schedule that alone but
then also uh just like my job like I
work I'm a free I work in the live event
industry so I'm just a gig worker like I
ran away like sometimes they'll be like
hey tomorrow can you work this thing all
day and I'm like
I guess but [__] my plans for tomorrow
so it's just hard to reschedule all
these podcasts and then I end up turning
down paid money for for a podcast guests
which I love doing but doesn't make the
money so it's is there a day of the week
that you like don't typically get those
phone calls like it's Monday like do you
not have to do events on Monday or is it
Tuesday you know I've I've thought about
that it's uh weekends certainly aren't
aren't the business like I'm very busy
on weekends and just I see a lot too so
that's that's a lot on the weekends but
um no I was thinking maybe Tuesdays and
basically
what I was thinking
um just to help myself with this whole
thing so I had two thoughts so much the
name of this for one I was thinking of
just doing Tuesdays I'd never take work
on Tuesdays pretty much never and I just
do
um podcasts and poetry because I'm just
starting this starting next Tuesday
um in San San Marcos me along with
someone else is we're hosting an open
mic poetry night in San Marcos at this
place uh let's concern do that every
Tuesday and so I was thinking take every
Tuesday off anyway do the podcasts every
Tuesday at least get one episode out
whether it's I've already pre-recorded
it or pre-record post
post an episode every day and record an
episode every or every Tuesday
I just said that confusing basically all
my podcasts work on Tuesdays that's what
I'm yeah
and that's what I was just getting at
like if you can if you could pick a day
um that could be your day
um that's how I would do it too hey do
you so as a podcast listener
there's something to be said about how
long I often wait because a lot of times
I take a long time to post and it loses
a little bit of the energy by then like
if it's a couple weeks after I post it
it'll lose a little bit of the energy do
you think if there was a live every
Tuesday at you know 11 A.M there's
either a live podcast or you know every
Tuesday at 11 A.M there's going to be a
new junkyard love podcast would you be
more prone to listen to it and watch
that as a podcast consumer if it's yeah
I think when when they're like you know
when like Bert Kreischer and Tom Score
like Bank a podcast and it's like and
they start talking about something
current and it's from a month ago I get
uninterested
um and I understand the business right
like they're super duper busy so I think
if you can like if you can record on a
Tuesday and have it out within you know
two Tuesdays of that I think that's
definitely healthier
um uh I think it would be tough for me
to like listen to a live like if you
know I would definitely tune in from
time to time but like from a scheduling
perspective like you know what I mean
like I don't know if I'd be able to like
pop in for like every Tuesday at 11
seven there's a live podcast being being
filmed I think that's cool
um but for me I do think it's kind of
important to like
I don't know get it out because not that
we touched on too many like yeah like
now that we touched on too many things
but like we kind of talked about you
know I was like I said you know that San
Francisco made mushrooms legal you know
this week so like right you know at the
time this is about a month from now then
like you know people can kind of time
stamp it which yeah you know
um that is part there is an aliveness to
posting it sooner than later for sure
definitely yeah I'm comfortable like I
don't you can you can you know whatever
I don't know what you have to do to like
to make it work but like you don't need
to cut anything that we talked about
from my side of things nice nice yeah
that's good I mean a lot of times I
don't have to but so one I record the
audio separately my my audio and so I
layer that over because I think it does
it sounds better than what Zoom records
um I also like adding an intro and an
outro so that's part of it and sometimes
I color correct a little bit too so it's
all things that I can live without like
I think I'd be fine I don't think
anybody's gonna stop listening to my
podcast because those things change a
little bit because because you color
corrected you know the blemishes on my
face yeah they're like yeah so it looks
you're looking a little pale Jake so
yeah but uh yeah I mean that's the art
of it I I think eventually
I mean a lot of what a lot of people do
is uh they'll have some sort of
assistant who handles all these things
and I just show up as the talent like
all I gotta do is interviews ideally
that would be a cool place to eventually
land but you know thus far I'm not not
in a position to be uh throwing money
into the podcast in such a way but uh I
do think I I think it would be cool so
uh this podcast to listen to Buddha at
the gas pump back Gap they do okay every
episode or every guest they do is live
but they also have
uh like an open like Facebook group and
a couple other things open at the same
time and so people can submit questions
in real time and he talks to them in
real time so it's like oh hey a question
just came in from you know Ann from
Kentucky and she asked you know this and
they and it helps the conversation
prayerfully so that is cool but then
they also it posts afterwards so it's
the live but then it's available I think
right afterwards like so whatever was
recorded is now available yeah that's
actually really cool I don't think it's
a bad idea to link that up with like you
and your buddy
um who have like an agenda thing you
want to talk about like you could do it
like
um like me just spitballing here but
like you do like a book club like Hey
we're gonna read this book and then
we're gonna do a live show and then that
way you know the people that want like
oh I read that book or yeah let me read
that book in the next month and then
they're in there on the live chat yeah I
like that that makes me cool
yeah any sort of interactive stuff
um that can you still hear me I can
still hear you yeah are your airpods
done you can hear me yeah yeah they just
died and I'm I'm honestly about to pee
my pants but okay all right well I'll
let you go brother uh man I really
appreciate you you're a wonderful person
I like that too it's it's great to even
know you let alone have you on my my
podcast man
um I really appreciate you uh let's
let's stay in touch and uh you know hit
me up once in a while and thanks again
man thank you I would uh I'd love to
come back yeah sounds good all right
everybody love yourself drink some water
stretch
um
and yeah just uh you know love your
family be a little more present when you
can find the time to just just be right
where you're at and just just enjoy that
it's a gift
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]